<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"   "docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <articleinfo>
  <title>My Expenses News
  </title>
    <author>
      <firstname>Michael</firstname>
      <surname>Totschnig</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>michael@totschnig.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
  <abstract><para>
      <application>My Expenses</application> is an app for tracking expenses and incomes with Android, designed
      for compatibility with desktop finance tools.
    </para>
  </abstract>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="news1">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
          We explain here the new feature introduced in 1.5.0: Payment methods
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2012-11-18</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>New in 1.5.0.: Payment methods</title>
    <para>
      Through this new channel, I will publish regularly explanations and discussions of
      <application>My Expenses</application>'s functionality. In contrast to the tutorial, which I
      try to keep consistent with the current release, and which is translated to all supported
      languages, these articles are meant to document new features, as they arise, to generate
      comments from users and hence to contribute to the app's continuos improvement.
    </para>
    <para>
      In answer to requests voiced already by its first users, version 1.5.0. of <application>My
      Expenses</application> introduced payment methods. The functionality is equivalent to how
      payment methods work in <application>Grisbi</application>: Payment methods are linked to
      accounts through account types. When you create an account, you define its type as one of CASH,
      BANK, ASSET or LIABILITY. When you create transactions in a given account, you can then make
      use of the payment methods that are linked to its account type. 
    </para>
    <para>
      Through the "Manage payment methods" activity from the preferences screen, you can change, add
      and delete methods.
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news1_1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news1_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      <application>My Expenses</application> has four predefined payment methods, all of them by
      default linked only to bank accounts: CHEQUE, CREDITCARD, DEPOSIT, DIRECTDEBIT. Those cannot
      be deleted, or renamed, but you can alter their association with account types. Clicking on a
      method or activating the "New" button brings you to the following screen:
    </para>
        <figure floatstyle="left" id="news1_2" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news1_2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Here you decide if the method should only be used for expenses (credit), incomes (debit), or
      both (neutral). And you check the account types where you want to make use of it. Now in the
      edit screen for transactions you will see a line labeled "Method", with a button opening the
      dialog where you select one of the applicable methods for the transaction.
    </para>
            <figure floatstyle="left" id="news1_3" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news1_3.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
    Unfortunately, payment methods are not yet expressed in the QIF export, because the standard
    does not provide a field for this information. If you have an idea on how to export transactions
    in a more expressive format, let me know.
    </para>
    </sect1>
   <sect1 id="news2">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
         We explain here a feature introduced by the upcoming 1.6.0 release: templates.
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2012-11-25</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>New feature in upcoming 1.6.0 release: Templates </title>
    <para>
      This article is in preparation. Please stay tuned.
    </para>
    </sect1>
</article>
