<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"   "docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <articleinfo>
  <title>My Expenses News
  </title>
    <author>
      <firstname>Michael</firstname>
      <surname>Totschnig</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>michael@totschnig.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
  <abstract><para>
      <application>My Expenses</application> is an app for tracking expenses and incomes with Android, designed
      for compatibility with desktop finance tools.
    </para>
  </abstract>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="news1">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
          We explain here the new feature introduced in 1.5.0: Payment methods
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2012-11-18</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>New in 1.5.0.: Payment methods</title>
    <para>
      Through this new channel, I will publish regularly explanations and discussions of
      <application>My Expenses</application>'s functionality. In contrast to the tutorial, which I
      try to keep consistent with the current release, and which is translated to all supported
      languages, these articles are meant to document new features, as they arise, to generate
      comments from users and hence to contribute to the app's continuos improvement.
    </para>
    <para>
      In answer to requests voiced already by its first users, version 1.5.0. of <application>My
      Expenses</application> introduced payment methods. The functionality is equivalent to how
      payment methods work in <application>Grisbi</application>: Payment methods are linked to
      accounts through account types. When you create an account, you define its type as one of CASH,
      BANK, ASSET or LIABILITY. When you create transactions in a given account, you can then make
      use of the payment methods that are linked to its account type.
    </para>
    <para>
      Through the "Manage payment methods" activity from the preferences screen, you can change, add
      and delete methods.
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news1_1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news1_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      <application>My Expenses</application> has four predefined payment methods, all of them by
      default linked only to bank accounts: CHEQUE, CREDITCARD, DEPOSIT, DIRECTDEBIT. Those cannot
      be deleted, or renamed, but you can alter their association with account types. Clicking on a
      method or activating the <guibutton>New</guibutton> button brings you to the following screen:
    </para>
        <figure floatstyle="left" id="news1_2" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news1_2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Here you decide if the method should only be used for expenses (credit), incomes (debit), or
      both (neutral). And you check the account types where you want to make use of it. Now in the
      edit screen for transactions you will see a line labeled <guilabel>Method</guilabel>, with a button opening the
      dialog where you select one of the applicable methods for the transaction.
    </para>
      <figure floatstyle="left" id="news1_3" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news1_3.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
    Unfortunately, payment methods are not yet expressed in the QIF export, because the standard
    does not provide a field for this information. If you have an idea on how to export transactions
    in a more expressive format, let me know.
    </para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="news2">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
         We explain here a feature introduced in 1.6.0: templates.
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2012-11-22</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>New feature in upcoming 1.6.0 release: Templates</title>
    <para>
      <application>My Expenses</application> now tries to help you enter recurrent transactions: say
      you often eat a fixed-priced meal in your favourite restaurant, or transfer the same amount of
      money from one account to the other, or buy the weekly magazine at your newsstand, you name it.
      After you have entered the transaction once, you call the <guilabel>Create template</guilabel> command from its context menu:
    </para>
     <figure floatstyle="left" id="news2_1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news2_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Enter a title for the template:
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news2_2" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news2_2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Templates are available through the <guibutton>New</guibutton>
      button's popup window.
    </para>
     <figure floatstyle="left" id="news2_3" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news2_3.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Clicking on a template's title results in the instantiation of a new transaction with all information
      (amount, category, comment, payee, payment method) from the template. Only time and date reflect
      the current moment.
   </para>
     <figure floatstyle="left" id="news2_4" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news2_4.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
   <para>
      In the same way you can define templates for transfers. Templates are linked to
      accounts, so you only see templates defined for the current account in the popup menu.
    </para>
    <para>
      Inspecting the list of templates and deleting the ones you no longer need, is available from
      the preferences.
    </para>
    <para>
      Beta 1 of 1.6.0 is available from Github's <ulink url="https://github.com/mtotschnig/MyExpenses/downloads">Downloads</ulink> and shortly through
      <ulink url="https://f-droid.org/repository/browse/?fdid=org.totschnig.myexpenses">F-Droid</ulink>.
    </para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="news3">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
         We explain here the new dark theme introduced in 1.6.1
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2013-01-19</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>Upcoming 1.6.1 release brings a new theme to <application>My Expenses</application></title>
    <para>
      Besides UI translation to Catalan, contributed by <ulink url="http://pacoriviere.cat/">Paco Rivière</ulink>,
      version 1.6.1, now available in alpha version for testing, will bring a dark theme, contributed by <ulink
        url="https://meinnoteblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/14/finanzverwaltung-mit-android/">meinnoteblog</ulink>.
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news3_1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news3_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para />
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news3_2" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news3_2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Please give the alpha version a try, or simply comment on what you think of the new theme below.
    </para>
    <para>
      Planned for 1.6.2 is the integration of another user contributed enhancement (by <ulink
        url="https://github.com/khris78/MyExpenses">khris78</ulink>), that will allow to associate a
      different color with each account.
    </para>
    <para>
      With this new theme, and your <ulink url="/en/participate.html">contribution</ulink>,
      <application>My Expenses</application> is on its way to become Android's best expense
      tracking app. ;-)
    </para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="news4">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
         1.7.0 allows to swipe through accounts, and introduces Contrib Features
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2013-04-22</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>Swipe and contribute</title>
    <para><application>My Expenses</application> 1.7.0 will hit Google Play in some days. If you manage
    multiple accounts, you will be able to navigate through them using the Swipe Gesture.
    It also introduces a couple of minor enhancements that have been requested for by users:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
    <para>You now can directly edit templates. Previously, you were required to delete a template,
    and create a new one, if you had needed some modification to its title or any other information.
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news4_1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news4_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>
    Now you can restore backups from the preferences screen. Previously, backups were automatically
    restored, when one was found during app installation. Thus, you needed to uninstall/reinstall
    <application>My Expenses</application>, in order to restore a backup. The restoration upon install
    is now no longer automatic, but confirmation is asked for.
    </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>
    Users that have set up multiple accounts with the same currency, will see a "Total" button in the
    accounts list, which displays the aggregate totals accross all accounts.
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news4_2" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news4_2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      Starting with 1.7.0, there is a new distribution model for <application>My
      Expenses</application>, through which I'd like to sollicit your contribution to the funding of
      the further development, in order to keep it free of advertisment and open source. Selected new features
      are handled as premium features. Those can be used five times for free, and then will be
      restricted to users having installed a paid Contrib app shortly available on Google Play.
      Users participating in the development of the app (e.g. as translators or beta testers), or
      prefering to donate through PayPal or Flattr (which by the way keep a lower percentage of the
      transaction amount to themselves), can request a key that will unlock the premium features
      without installation of the Contrib app. So please give the newest alpha
      version a try, and use the "Request Contrib Key" entry in the preferences screen. I
      will usually answer these requests in less than 24 hours.
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news4_3" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news4_3.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </sect1>
    
    <sect1 id="news5">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
         New in 1.7.1: password protection
        </para>
      </abstract>
      <pubdate>2013-05-05</pubdate>
    </sect1info>
    <title>Password protection</title>
    <para>
      The feature most frequently requested by users in their comments on Google Play is password
      protection. It will be available with <application>My Expenses</application> 1.7.1 and can
      already be tested in the <ulink url="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/myexpenses/MyExpenses-1.7.1a1.apk">alpha version</ulink>.
      The password can be set from the settings screen, and will be checked every time the app is started,
      or resumed after a delay of more than 10 seconds. The protection is global to the whole application,
      i.e. it covers not only the main transaction list, but all secondary screens (e.g. when you leave
      the app while editing an expense, selecting a category, or changing a configuration setting etc.).
    </para>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="news5_1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="news5_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    </sect1>
</article>
