<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"   "docbookx.dtd">
<article>
  <articleinfo>
  <title> <application role="app_name"/>
    <phrase lang="en">Tutorial</phrase>
    <phrase lang="fr">Tutoriel</phrase>
    <phrase lang="de">Anleitung</phrase>
    <phrase lang="it">Tutorial</phrase>
    <phrase lang="es">Instrucciones</phrase>
  </title>
    <author>
      <firstname>Michael</firstname>
      <surname>Totschnig</surname>
      <affiliation>
        <address><email>michael@totschnig.org</email></address>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
    <othercredit lang="fr">
    <firstname>Laurent</firstname>
    <surname>Collombet</surname>
    <contrib>Traduction française</contrib>
  </othercredit>
  <othercredit lang="it">
    <firstname>Laurent</firstname>
    <surname>Collombet</surname>
    <contrib>Traduzione italiana</contrib>
  </othercredit>
  <othercredit lang="it">
    <firstname>Gudrun</firstname>
    <surname>Totschnig</surname>
    <contrib>Traduzione italiana</contrib>
  </othercredit>
  <othercredit lang="es">
    <firstname>Gudrun</firstname>
    <surname>Totschnig</surname>
    <contrib>Traducción al español</contrib>
  </othercredit>
    <othercredit lang="es">
    <firstname>Christof</firstname>
    <surname>Totschnig</surname>
    <contrib>Traducción al español</contrib>
  </othercredit>
  <othercredit lang="es">
    <firstname>Johanna</firstname>
    <surname>Totschnig</surname>
    <contrib>Traducción al español</contrib>
  </othercredit>
  <abstract>
    <para lang="en">
      <application role="app_name"/> is an app for tracking expenses and incomes with Android, designed
      for compatibility with desktop finance tools.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
    <application role="app_name"/>  est un app de suivi des entrées d'argent et des
      dépenses, compatible avec les logiciel de finance.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      <application role="app_name"/> ist eine App für die Buchhaltung über Einnahmen und Ausgaben,
      kompatibel mit Desktop-Finanzprogrammmen.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      <application role="app_name"/> è una app por l'offerta di moneta e le spese, compatibile con
      un software di finanza
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      <application role="app_name"/> es una app de contabilidad sobre gastos e ingresos,compatible con
      las programas de escritorio de finanzas.
    </para>
  </abstract>
  <releaseinfo lang="en">This release (3) of the tutorial describes versions of
    <application role="app_name"/> below 1.6.0. Please consider <ulink url="market://details?id=org.totschnig.myexpenses">upgrading</ulink> and
    consult the <ulink url="http://myexpenses.totschnig.org/?lang=en#tutorial_r4">current
    release</ulink> (4) of this document.
  </releaseinfo>
  <releaseinfo lang="fr">Cette édition (3) du tutoriel décrit la version de
    <application role="app_name"/> antérieure à 1.6.0. Pensez à la  <ulink url="market://details?id=org.totschnig.myexpenses">mettre à jour</ulink> et
    consultez <ulink url="http://myexpenses.totschnig.org/?lang=fr#tutorial_r4">l'édition
    actuelle</ulink> (4) de ce document.
  </releaseinfo>
  <releaseinfo lang="de">Diese Ausgabe (3) der Anleitung beschreibt Versionen
  von <application role="app_name"/> vor 1.6.0. Vergessen Sie nicht, die App
   <ulink url="market://details?id=org.totschnig.myexpenses">upzudaten</ulink> und sehen Sie sich die <ulink
  url="http://myexpenses.totschnig.org/?lang=de#tutorial_r4">aktuelle Ausgabe</ulink> (4)
  dieses Dokumentes an.
  </releaseinfo>
  <releaseinfo lang="it">Questa edizione (3) del tutorial descrive la versione di
    <application role="app_name"/> prima 1.6.0. Ricordarsi di 
    <ulink url="market://details?id=org.totschnig.myexpenses">aggiornare</ulink> e consulta 
    <ulink url="http://myexpenses.totschnig.org/?lang=it#tutorial_r4">l'attuale edizione </ulink> (4) di questo documento.
  </releaseinfo>
  <releaseinfo lang="es">Esta versión (3) del guía describe versiones de <application role="app_name"/>
    inferior a la 1.6.0. Por favor, considere <ulink url="market://details?id=org.totschnig.myexpenses">actualizar</ulink>
    y consulte la <ulink url="http://myexpenses.totschnig.org/?lang=es#tutorial_r4">versión actual</ulink> (4) de este documento. 
  </releaseinfo>
  </articleinfo>

  <sect1 id="introduction">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para lang="en">
          General usage information.
        </para>
        <para lang="fr">
          Information générale sur l'usage.
        </para>
        <para lang="de">
          Allgemeine Information zur Verwendung
        </para>
        <para lang="it">
          Informazioni generali di utilizzo
        </para>
        <para lang="es">
          Información de uso general
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info>
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Introduction</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Introduction</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Einleitung</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Introduzione</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Introducción</phrase>
    </title>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step1" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <!-- BEGIN introduction para 1 -->    
    <para lang="en">
      <application role="app_name"/> is designed to keep track of your expenses and incomes,
      and to export these expenses into a desktop finance tool, like Grisbi or Gnucash. It
      supports multiple accounts and a two-level hierarchy of categories.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      <application role="app_name"/>  permet de gérer les entrées d'argent et les
      dépenses, et de les exporter vers un logiciel de finance, tel que Grisbi ou Gnucash.
      Il supporte de multiples comptes et deux niveaux de catégories.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Mit <application role="app_name"/> können sie über Ihre Ausgaben und Einnahmen Buch
      halten, und diese in ein Desktop-Finanzprogrammm (Grisbi oder Gnucash) exportieren. Es
      unterstützt mehrere Konten und zwei Ebenen von Kategorien.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      <application role="app_name"/> può gestire l'offerta di moneta e le spese, ed esportarle
      in un software di finanza, come Grisbi o GnuCash. Esso supporta più conti e due livelli
      di categorie.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Con <application role="app_name"/> puede llevar contabilidad sobre sus gastos e ingresos,
      y controlar y exportar estos a un programa de escritorio de finanzas. Puede manejar
      varias cuentas y dos grupos de categorías. 
    </para>
    <!-- END introduction para 1 -->  

    <!-- BEGIN introduction para 2 -->    
    <para lang="en">
      Its main screen displays the list of transactions for the current account. The button bar
      displayed at the bottom of the screen gives easy access to all functionalities. Each
      button executes a default action on short clicks and most open up a menu with further
      actions on long clicks. Alternatively, you can configure <application role="app_name"/>
      in <link linkend='tutorial5_6'><guilabel role="pref_use_standard_menu_title"/></link> to
      use a command interface based on the Android standard menu.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Sur l'écran principal s'affiche la liste des transactions du compte en cours. La
      barre des boutons en bas de l'écran donne accès à toutes les fonctions. Chaque
      bouton exécute une action par défaut sur un clic court. La plupart
      affichent un menu avec d'autres actions sur un clic long. Sinon, vous 
      pouvez configurer <application role="app_name"/> afin qu'il utilise le menu
      standard d'Android en tant qu'interface de commande (<link linkend='tutorial5_6'><guilabel
      	role="pref_use_standard_menu_title"/></link> ).
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      In der Hauptansicht werden alle Buchungen des aktiven Kontos angezeigt. Am unteren Rand
      des Bildschirms befinded sich eine Symbolleiste, die Zugriff auf alle Funktionalitäten
      gewährt. Jeder Schaltknopf ruft mittels eines kurzen Klicks eine Aktion auf, die meisten
      reagieren zusätzlich auf einen langen Klick, und öffnen ein Menü mit weiteren Aktionen.
      Anstatt der Menüleiste kann <application role="app_name"/> auch das Android Standardmenü
      verwenden, wenn sie <link linkend='tutorial5_6'><guilabel
      	role="pref_use_standard_menu_title"/></link> konfigurieren.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Nella schermata principale mostra un elenco di operazioni in conto corrente. La barra
      nella parte inferiore dello schermo fornisce accesso a tutte le funzioni. Ogni pulsante
      esegue un'azione predefinita in risposta a un clic breve. La maggior parte visualizza
      un menu con altre azioni in un clic lungo. In caso contrario, è possibile configurare que
      <application role="app_name"/> utilizza il menù standard di Android come
      interfaccia di controllo(<link linkend='tutorial5_6'><guilabel
      	role="pref_use_standard_menu_title"/></link>).
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      En la ventana principal puede ver todos los asientos de su cuenta activa. En la parte
      inferior de la ventana se encuentra una barra de herramientas por la cual se llega a
      todas las funcionalidades. Cada botón inicia con un clic breve una acción, y casi todos
      los botones abren con un clic largo un menú con mas acciones. En lugar de la barra de
      menú <application role="app_name"/> puede utilizar también el menú estándar de Android si
      usted configura <link linkend='tutorial5_6'><guilabel role="pref_use_standard_menu_title"
      	/></link>.
    </para>    
    <!-- END introduction para 2 -->
    
  </sect1>
  
    <!-- Tutorial1 -->
    
  <sect1 id="tutorial1">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para lang="en">
          How to manage accounts
        </para>
        <para lang="fr">
          Commment gérer les comptes
        </para>
        <para lang="de">
          Wie man Konton verwaltet
        </para>
        <para lang="it">
          Como gestire gli conti
        </para>
        <para lang="es">
          Cómo administrar las cuentas
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info>
    <title id="tutorial1.title">
      <phrase lang="en">Accounts</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Comptes</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Konten</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Conti</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Las cuentas</phrase>
    </title>

    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step2" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <!-- BEGIN tutorial1 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      When you launch <application role="app_name"/> for the first time, there is one default
      account defined and you can immediatly start adding transactions. If you want to edit
      the default account, use  
      <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_settings"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_settings_account"/>
     </menuchoice>, whereas
     <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_accounts"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_accounts_new"/>
     </menuchoice> allows to create a new account.
    </para>

    <para lang="fr">
      Lors du premier lancement de <application role="app_name"/>, un compte par défaut est
      créé, et vous pouvez commencer immédiatement
à saisir des transactions. Si vous voulez
      éditer celui-ci, utilisez
      <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_settings"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_settings_account"/>
     </menuchoice>. Si vous désirez en créer un nouveau, activez
     <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_accounts"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_accounts_new"/>
     </menuchoice>.
    </para>

    <para lang="de">
      Beim ersten Aufruf von <application role="app_name"/> wird ein Standardkonto
      angelegt, und Sie können sofort mit der Eingabe von Buchungen beginnen. Falls Sie
      das Standardkonto verändern wollen, verwenden Sie 
      <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_settings"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_settings_account"/>
      </menuchoice>. Mittels
      <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_accounts"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_accounts_new"/>
     </menuchoice>
     hingegen können Sie ein neues Konto anlegen.
    </para>

    <para lang="it">
       Al primo avvio di <application role="app_name"/>, un conto predefinito è stato creato, e
       si può immediatamente iniziare a inserire le transazioni. Se si desidera modificare il
       conto predefinito, utilizzare
      <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_settings"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_settings_account"/>
     </menuchoice>Se si desidera creare un nuovo conto, seleziona
     <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_accounts"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_accounts_new"/>
     </menuchoice>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Cuando se abre <application role="app_name"/> por primera vez se configura
      automáticamente una cuenta estándar y usted puede empezar a insertar sus asientos en
      seguida. Si quiere modificar la cuenta estándar, utilice
      <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_settings"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_settings_account"/>
     </menuchoice>. A través de
     <menuchoice>
        <guimenu role="menu_accounts"/>
        <guimenuitem role="menu_accounts_new"/>
     </menuchoice> en cambio puede configurar una nueva cuenta.
   </para>    
    <!-- END tutorial1 para 1 --> 

    <!-- BEGIN tutorial1 para 2 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      Enter a label, a description, the opening balance<footnoteref linkend="ftn22-en-1"/>
      and a currency for the account. The currency must be entered according to
      its three-letter code in ISO 4217, but can be chosen easily from a list by clicking on
      the <guibutton role="select"/> button.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Entrez un libellé, une description, le solde d'ouverture<footnoteref
      linkend="ftn22-fr-1"/> et la devise de ce compte. La devise doit être saisie selon le
      code ISO 4217 en trois lettres, mais peut être facilement sélectionné sur une
      liste en cliquant sur <guibutton role="select"/>
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Geben Sie eine Bezeichnung, eine Beschreibung, den Anfangssaldo<footnoteref
      linkend="ftn22-de-1"/> und die Währung des Kontos ein. Die Währung muss anhand ihrer
      dreistelligen Abkürzung ISO 4217 eingegeben werden, aber kann durch Klick auf <guibutton
      role="select"/> einfach aus einer Liste ausgewählt werden.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Inserire una etichetta, una descrizione, il saldo di apertura<footnoteref
      linkend="ftn22-it-1"/>, e una valuta per il conto. La valuta deve essere inserita secondo
      la ISO 4217 di tre lettere, ma può essere facilmente selezionato da una lista, fare clic
      <guibutton role="select"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Inserte un nombre, una descripción, el saldo inicial<footnoteref
      linkend="ftn22-es-1"/> y la moneda de la cuenta. La moneda
      va insertada con su abreviación de tres cifras ISO 4217, pero puede ser elegida
      simplemente de la lista, a la cual se llega con un clic sobre <guibutton role="select"/>.
    </para>    
    <!-- END tutorial1 para 2 -->
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial1 para 3 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      You can define the type of an account as one of Cash, Bank, Asset, Liabilities. Account types
      are associated with payment methods, as explained in <link linkend='tutorial5_9'><guilabel
        role="pref_manage_methods_title"/></link>. Here we will define the account as bank account, 
      in order to demonstrate the use of payment methods. 
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Vous pouvez associer le compte aux types suivants: compte de caisse, compte bancaire,  compte
      d'actif ou compte de passif. Les méthodes de paiement sont définies par type de compte, tel 
      qu'indiqué dans <link linkend='tutorial5_9'><guilabel role="pref_manage_methods_title"/></link>.
      Ici nous choisissons compte bancaire, afin de pouvoir montrer l'utilisation des méthodes de paiement.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Sie können einem Konto einem der folgenden Typen zuordnen: Bargeldkonto, Bankkonto, Anlagekonto, 
      Kreditkonto. Für Kontotypen sind Zahlungsweisen definiert, wie in <link
        linkend='tutorial5_9'><guilabel role="pref_manage_methods_title"/></link> beschrieben. Hier
      wählen wir den Typ als Bankkonto, um zu zeigen, wie Zahlungsweisen verwendet werden.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Puo assegnare qualsiasi conto a uno dei seguenti tipi: Conto di denaro contante, conto
      bancario, conto d’investimento, conto d’accredito. Per i tipi di conti sono definiti modi di
      pagamento, com’è definito in <link linkend='tutorial5_9'><guilabel
        role="pref_manage_methods_title"/></link>. Qui scegliamo come tipo il conto bancario, per
      dimostrare come si usano i modi di pagamento.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Usted puede asignar a una cuenta uno de los siguientes tipos: cuenta de caja, cuenta bancaria,
      cuenta de inversiones, cuenta de crédito. Para los tipos de cuenta están definidos métodos de
      pago como se definen en <link linkend='tutorial5_9'><guilabel
        role="pref_manage_methods_title"/></link>. Aquí elegimos el tipo de cuenta bancaria para
      mostrar cómo se utilizan los métodos de pago.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial1 para 3 -->
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial1 para 4 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      When you confirm that you are done, you get back to the transaction list. If you
      have created a new account, it is automatically set to be the current account.
      You can easily switch between accounts through the <guibutton role="menu_accounts"/>
      button. A short click switches to the last active account, a long click gives access
      to a menu of all accounts.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Confirmez, et vous reviendrez à la liste des transactions. Si vous avez ajouté un
      nouveau compte, celui-ci deviendra automatiquement le compte en cours. Le bouton
      <guibutton role="menu_accounts"/> permet de facilement changer de compte.
      Un clic court active le dernier utilisé, un clic long ouvre le  menu
      permettant de le choisir dans la liste complète.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Nach Bestätigung der Eingabe gelangen Sie wieder zur Liste der Buchungen. Wenn Sie
      ein neues Konto angelegt haben, wird dieses automatisch zum aktiven Konto. Der
      Schaltknopf <guibutton role="menu_accounts"/> erlaubt das Wechseln zwischen Konton.
      Ein einfacher Klick wechselt zum zuletzt aktiven Konto, ein langer Klick öffnet ein
      Menü mit allen Konten zur Auswahl.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Confermare la voce, e si ritorna alla lista di transazioni. Se si è aggiunto un nuovo
      conto, diventa automaticamente il conto corrente. La voce <guibutton
      role="menu_accounts"/> consente di cambiare il conto corrente. Un clic breve attiva il
      conto ultimo utilizzato, un clic lungo apre un menu per scegliere questo dalla lista.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Después de confirmar su inserción el programa vuelve a la lista de sus asientos. Si
      configura una nueva cuenta, esa se trasforma automáticamente en la cuenta activa. El
      botón <guibutton role="menu_accounts"/> permite cambiar de una cuenta a otra. Con un clic
      simple se vuelve a la cuenta recientemente activa, un clic largo abre un menú con todas
      las cuentas a elegir.
    </para>    
    <!-- END tutorial1 para 4 --> 
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial1 para 5 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      For managing the complete account list, please refer to <link linkend='tutorial5_1'
      	><guilabel role="pref_manage_accounts_title"/></link>.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      La gestion des comptes est expliqué dans <link linkend='tutorial5_1'><guilabel 
      	role="pref_manage_accounts_title"/></link>.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Die Verwaltung der Konten wird in <link linkend='tutorial5_1'><guilabel
      	role="pref_manage_accounts_title"/></link> erklärt.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      La gestione dei conti è spiegata in <link linkend='tutorial5_1'><guilabel
      	role="pref_manage_accounts_title"/></link>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      La administración de las cuentas se explica en <link linkend='tutorial5_1'><guilabel
      	role="pref_manage_accounts_title"/></link>
    </para>    
    <!-- END tutorial1 para 5 --> 
  </sect1>
   
   <!-- Tutorial2 -->
  <sect1 id="tutorial2">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para lang="en">
          How to manage transactions
        </para>
        <para lang="fr">
          Commment gérer les opérations
        </para>
        <para lang="de">
          Wie man Buchungen verwaltet
        </para>
        <para lang="it">
          Como gestire gli transazioni
        </para>
        <para lang="es">
          Cómo administrar los asientos
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info>
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Transactions</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Opérations</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Buchungen</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Transazioni</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Los asientos</phrase>
    </title>
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step3" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step3.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial2 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      A short click on <guibutton role="menu_new"/> brings up  the activity for creating a
      transaction.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      <guimenuitem role="menu_new"/> vous ouvre la fenêtre pour créer une opération.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Kurzer Klick auf <guibutton role="menu_new"/> öffnet den Bildschirm für die Eingabe einer
      neuen Buchung.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      <guimenuitem role="menu_new"/> porta in primo piano l'attività 
      per la creazione di una transazione.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Un clic breve sobre <guimenuitem role="menu_new"/> abre una ventana para la inserción de
      un nuevo asiento.
    </para>    
    <!-- END tutorial2 para 1 --> 
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial2 para 2 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      Adjust date and time, click on the <guibutton>-</guibutton> Button to toggle between
      expense and income, enter amount<footnote id="ftn22-en-1">
        <para>
          The input format for currency amounts can be configured through the <link
          linkend='tutorial5_8'><guilabel role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_title"/></link>
          setting.
       </para>
      </footnote> and notes. The payee (or payer) field remembers the
      values you enter and will suggest them in the future<footnote id="ftn22-en-2">
        <para>
          You can also import a list of parties for autocompleting the payee field from your
          Grisbi file as explained in <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
            role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. If you want to delete entries from
          this list refer to <link linkend='tutorial5_7'><guilabel
            role="pref_manage_parties_title"/></link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Clicking on the
      <guibutton role="select"/> button next to <guilabel role="category" />, brings up the <guilabel 
        role="select_category"/> activity. We will explain below, how to manage categories.
    </para>
    
    <para lang="fr">
      Fixez la date et l'heure, cliquez sur le bouton <guibutton>-</guibutton> pour
      basculer entre dépense ou entrée, entrez la somme<footnote id="ftn22-fr-1">
        <para>
          Le format d'entrée des montants peut être configuré par le paramètre
          <link linkend='tutorial5_8'><guilabel role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_title"/></link>
        </para>
     </footnote> et une remarque.
      Le champ Tiers mémorise les valeurs que vous entrez, et les suggérera la prochaine fois
      que vous entrerez un tiers<footnote id="ftn22-fr-2">
        <para>
          Vous pouvez importer la liste des tiers enregistrés de votre fichier Grisbi, comme
          expliqué dans <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
            role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. Si vous désirez supprimer des valeurs
          de cette liste, consultez <link linkend='tutorial5_7'><guilabel
            role="pref_manage_parties_title"/></link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Cliquer sur le bouton <guibutton role="select"/> 
      à côté de <guilabel role="category" />,vous ouvre la fenêtre
      <guilabel role="select_category"/>. Nous vous expliquerons plus tard
      comment gérer les catégories.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Passen Sie Datum und Uhrzeit an, klicken Sie auf den Schaltknopf <guibutton>-</guibutton>
      um zwischen Ausgabe und Einnahme zu wechseln, geben Sie Betrag<footnote id="ftn22-de-1">
        <para>
          Das Eingabeformat für Währungsbeträge kann mittels <link linkend='tutorial5_8'><guilabel
          role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_title"/></link>
          eingestellt werden.
       </para>
      </footnote> und Notizen ein.
      Das Feld für die Eingabe von Empfänger (bzw. Zahler) merkt sich die von Ihnen
      eingegebenen Werte, und schlägt diese bei weiteren Eingaben in diesem Feld 
      vor<footnote id="ftn22-de-2">
        <para>
          Sie können auch die in einer Grisbi Datei gespeicherte Liste der Parteien importieren
          (erklärt in <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
          role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>). Wie Sie Werte aus dieser Liste
          löschen können, erfahren Sie unter <link linkend='tutorial5_7'><guilabel
          role="pref_manage_parties_title"/></link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Durch Klick auf den Knopf
      <guibutton role="select"/> kommen Sie zum Bildschirm <guilabel role="select_category"/>.
      Dieser wird später erklärt.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Regolare data e ora, fare clico sul pulsante <guibutton>-</guibutton> per passare gli
      oneri ei proventi, inserire importo<footnote id="ftn22-it-1">
        <para>
          Il formato di ingresso per gli importi in valuta può essere configurato attraverso il parametro
	   <link linkend='tutorial5_8'><guilabel role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_title"/></link>
       </para>
       </footnote>, le note e il beneficiario (o debitore). Il
      benficiario campo memorizza i valori inseriti, e suggeriscono la prossima volta che si
      entra questo<footnote id="ftn22-it-2">
        <para>
          È possibile importare una lista di beneficiari iscritti nel file Grisbi, come
          spiegato in <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
          role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. Se si desidera eliminare valori da
          questo elenco, vedere <link linkend='tutorial5_7'><guilabel
          role="pref_manage_parties_title"/></link>.
        </para>
      </footnote> Cliccando sul <guibutton role="select"/> pulsante, si apre la <guilabel
      role="select_category"/> attività. Vi spiegheremo di seguito, come gestire le categorie.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
    <!-- Fußnoten fehlen -->
      Ajuste la fecha y la hora, presione el botón <guibutton>-</guibutton> para alternar entre
      gasto u ingreso, inserte el importe<footnote id="ftn22-es-1">
        <para>
          El formato de inserción para valores monetarios puede ser configurado por la
          configuración <link linkend='tutorial5_8'><guilabel
          role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_title"/></link>
        </para>
      </footnote> y apuntes. La casilla para la inserción del
      beneficiario (o del pagador) memoriza los valores que usted ha insertado, y se los
      propone si usted vuelve a hacer inserciones en esta casilla<footnote id="ftn22-es-2">
        <para>
          Puede también importar la lista de partes guardado en un archivo de Grisbi (se
          explica en <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
          role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>). Como borrar valores de esta lista
          léase en <link linkend='tutorial5_7'><guilabel
          role="pref_manage_parties_title"/></link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Con un clic sobre el botón
      <guibutton role="select"/> usted llega a la ventana <guilabel role="select_category"/>.
      Este punto se explica mas adelante.
    </para>    
    <!-- END tutorial2 para 2 -->
    <?float-clear?> 
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step4" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step4.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial2 para 3 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      If the current account is of a type, that is associated with payment methods, you can set the transaction's method
      through the <guibutton role="select"/> button next to <guilabel role="method" />.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Si le type du compte en cours est associé avec des méthodes de paiement, vous pouvez en choisir 
      une pour l'opération avec le bouton <guibutton role="select"/> à côté de <guilabel
        role="method" />, 
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Falls dem Typ des aktuellen Kontos Zahlungsweisen zugeordnet sind, können Sie durch den
      Schaltknopf <guibutton role="select"/> neben <guilabel  role="method" /> die Zahlungsweise der
      Buchung definieren. 
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Se il tipo del conto corrente è associato con un modo di pagamento, può definire attraverso la
      voce Selezionare accanto al Modo di pagamento il modo di pagamento della transazione.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Si el tipo de la cuenta corriente está asociado con métodos de pago, usted puede definir el
      método de pago del asiento a través de un clic sobre el botón <guibutton role="select"/> al 
      lado de <guilabel  role="method" />.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial2 para 3-->
    <?float-clear?> 

    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step5" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step5.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial2 para 3 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      Back at the transaction list, you can edit individual entries through a short click,
      the context menu allows deleting a transaction, or display full details (payee,
      notes) about it. You can also move a transaction to a different account, provided you
      have set up at least one additional account. 
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Sur la liste des opérations, vous pouvez éditer chaque opération avec un clic court,
      le menu contextuel vous permet aussi d'effacer une opération ou d'afficher tous ses
      détails (tiers, remarques). Vous pouvez aussi déplacer une opération vers un autre
      compte, si vous en avez créé au moins deux.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      In der Liste der Buchungen, kann jede Buchung durch einen kurzen Klick bearbeitet
      werden, das Kontextmenü erlaubt das Löschen und die Anzeige von Detailinformationen
      (Empfänger, Notizen). Sie können eine Buchung auch in ein anderes Konto verschieben,
      sofern sie zumindest ein weiteres Konto angelegt haben.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Ritorno alla lista transazione, è possibile modificare le singole voci attraverso un
      click breve, il menù contestuale permette di cancellare una transazione, o visualizzare
      tutti i dettagli (beneficiario, note). È inoltre possibile spostare una transazione ad
      un altro conto, se si dispone di almeno due conti
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      En la lista de los asientos puede editar con un breve clic cada asiento, el menú de
      contextual permite borrar y ver las informaciones detalladas (el beneficiario, apuntes).
      Puede mover un asiento de una cuenta a otra si es que usted haya configurado por lo
      menos una cuenta adicional.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial2 para 3 --> 
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial2_1">
      <title>
        <phrase lang="en">Transfer</phrase>
        <phrase lang="fr">Virement</phrase>
        <phrase lang="de">Umbuchung</phrase>
        <phrase lang="it">Trasferimento</phrase>
        <phrase lang="es">Traspaso entre cuentas</phrase>
      </title>
      
      <!-- BEGIN tutorial2_1 para 1 --> 
      <para lang="en">
        <menuchoice>
          <guimenu role="menu_new"/>
          <guimenuitem role="transfer"/>
       </menuchoice> allows you to transfer money between accounts. This command is enabled
       only if you have more than one account with the same currency as the current one.
      </para>
      <para lang="fr">
        <menuchoice>
          <guimenu role="menu_new"/>
          <guimenuitem role="transfer"/>
       </menuchoice> vous permet de virer une somme entre comptes. Cette commande n'est active
       que si vous avez au moins deux comptes dans la même devise.
      </para>
      <para lang="de">
        <menuchoice>
          <guimenu role="menu_new"/>
          <guimenuitem role="transfer"/>
       </menuchoice> erlaubt Beträge zwichen Konten zu verschieben. Dieser Befehl steht nur zur
       Verfügung, wenn es mehrere Konten mit derselben Währung gibt.
      </para>
      <para lang="it">
        <menuchoice>
          <guimenu role="menu_new"/>
          <guimenuitem role="transfer"/>
       </menuchoice> consente di trasferire denaro tra conti. Questo comando è disponibile solo
       se si dispone di più di uno conto con la stessa valuta di quella attuale.
      </para>
      <para lang="es">
        <menuchoice>
          <guimenu role="menu_new"/>
          <guimenuitem role="transfer"/>
       </menuchoice> permite trasladar importes de una cuenta a otra. Este mando <!-- (¿) -->  está a
       disposición solamente si existen varias cuentas de la misma moneda.
      </para>      
      <!-- END tutorial2_1 para 1 --> 
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
   
   <!-- Tutorial3 -->
  <sect1 id="tutorial3">
    <sect1info>
        <abstract>
        <para lang="en">
          How to manage categories
        </para>
        <para lang="fr">
          Commment gérer les catégories
        </para>
        <para lang="de">
          Wie man Kategorien verwaltet
        </para>
        <para lang="it">
          Como gestire gli categorie
        </para>
        <para lang="es">
          Cómo administrar las categorías
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info>
    <title>    
      <phrase lang="en">Categories</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Catégories</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Kategorien</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Categorie</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Categorías</phrase>
    </title>
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step6" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step6.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial3 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      At the beginning, no categories are defined. You have two options for adding them.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Au départ, aucune catégorie n'est prédéfinie. Vous avez deux possibilités pour les
      ajouter.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Zu Beginn gibt es noch keine Kategorien. Es gibt zwei Möglichkeiten,
      diese anzulegen.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      All'inizio, categorie non sono definite. Sono disponibili due opzioni per l'aggiunta di
      loro.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Al principio todavía no existen categorías.  Hay dos posibilidades de configurarlos.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial3 para 1 --> 
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial3 para 2 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      Either you click on the button <guibutton role="import_categories"/> which allows to
      select between different sources, as explained in <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
      	role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. This button is visible, only as
      long the categories list is stil empty, later you can always access the import
      functionality from the <guilabel role="menu_settings"/> activity.
      </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Soit vous cliquez sur le bouton <guibutton role="import_categories"/> qui vous permet de
      les entrer directement à partir des différents source, tel qu'expliqué dans <link
      	linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. Ce bouton
      est visible lorsque la liste des catégories est vide, mais vous pouvez toujours accéder à
      la fonction d'import à partir de l'écran <guilabel role="menu_settings"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Der Schaltknopf <guibutton role="import_categories"/> erlaubt Kategorien aus
      verschiedenen Quellen zu importieren wie in <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
      	role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link> erklärt. Dieser Schaltknopf
      ist nur sichtbar solange es keine Kategorien gibt, aber Sie können jederzeit im
      Bildschirm <guilabel role="menu_settings"/> auf die Import-Funktionalität zugreifen.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      O si sceglie <guibutton role="import_categories"/> che consente di immettere direttamente
      dalla fonte diversa, come spiegato nel <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
      	role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. Questo pulsante è visibile quando l'elenco
      delle categorie è vuoto, ma è ancora possibile accedere al funzione di importazione dallo
      schermo <guilabel role="menu_settings"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      El botón <guibutton role="import_categories"/> permite importar categorías de distintas
      fuentes como se explica en <link linkend='tutorial5_5'><guilabel
      	role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/></link>. Este botón está visible solamente mientras
      no existan categorías, pero en la ventana <guilabel role="menu_settings"/> usted puede
      acceder cuando quiera a la funcionalidad de importar.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial3 para 2 -->
    
    <?float-clear?> 
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step8" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step8.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <!-- BEGIN tutorial3 para 3 --> 
    <para lang="en">
	    You now have a set of categories with subcategories you can associate with your
	    transactions. By default, the primary sort criteria in the category list is the number of
	    times you use a category (the secondary criteria is alphabetical order). This gives you
	    quick access to the categories you use most often. If you prefer to have the categories
	    sorted in plain alphabetical order, you can configure <link linkend='tutorial5_2'><guilabel
	      role="pref_categories_sort_by_usages_title"/></link>.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Vous avez maintenant une liste de catégories et de sous-catégories que vous
      pouvez utiliser pour vos opérations. Par défaut, les catégories sont triées par la
      fréquence de leur utilisation (l'ordre alphabetique est utilisé en tant que critère
      secondaire). Ce fonctionnement vous donne un accès rapide aux catégories associées aux 
      transactions les plus utilisées. Si vous préferez voir apparaître les
      catégories dans l'ordre alphabétique, vous pouvez désactiver ce paramètre <link
        linkend='tutorial5_2'><guilabel role="pref_categories_sort_by_usages_title"/></link>.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Sie können die importierten Kategorien und Unterkategorien jetzt Ihren Buchungen
      zuordnen. Als primäres Sortierkriterium wird standardmäßig die Anzahl der Verwendungen
      einer Kategorie verwendet (sekundäres Kriterium ist die alphabetische Reihenfolge).
      Dadurch haben Sie zu den am häufigsten verwendeten Kategorien am schnellsten Zugriff.
      Wenn Sie die Kategorien lieber alphabetisch geordnet wollen, können Sie die Einstellung
      <guilabel role="pref_categories_sort_by_usages_title"/> deaktivieren.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Ora avete un elenco di categorie con sottocategorie che è possibile associare con il tuo
      transazioni. Per impostazione predefinita, le categorie sono ordinate per frequenza di
      utilizzo (in ordine alfabetico viene utilizzato come criterio secondario). Questa
      funzione consente di accedere rapidamente alle categorie relative alle operazioni che si
      utilizzano più. Se si preferisce vedere le categorie appaiono in ordine alfabetico, è
      possibile disabilitare questa impostazione <guilabel
      role="pref_categories_sort_by_usages_title"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Ahora puede atribuir las categorías y subcategorías a sus asientos. Como primer criterio
      de clasificación se utiliza el número de usos de una categoría (el segundo criterio es el
      orden alfabético). Así usted puede acceder de manera muy rápida a las categorías de uso
      mas frecuente. Si usted prefiere el orden alfabético puede desactivar la configuración
      <guilabel role="pref_categories_sort_by_usages_title"/>.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial3 para 3 --> 
    
    <?float-clear?> 
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step9" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step9.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial3 para 4 --> 
    <para lang="en">
	    The second option is to add your own categories.  <guibutton
	    role="menu_create_main_cat"/> brings up a dialog for providing a new category label.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      La seconde façon est d'ajouter vos propres catégories. <guibutton
      role="menu_create_main_cat"/> vous ouvre une fenêtre pour entrer un nouveau libellé.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Die zweite Möglichkeit besteht darin, Kategorien selbst anzulegen. <guibutton
      role="menu_create_main_cat"/> öffnet einen Dialog zur Eingabe einer Bezeichnung.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      La seconda opzione è quella di aggiungere proprie categorie. <guibutton
      role="menu_create_main_cat"/> porta in primo piano una finestra di dialogo per la
      fornitura di una nuova etichetta di categoria.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      La segunda posibilidad consiste en crear categorías por su cuenta. <guibutton
        role="menu_create_main_cat"/> principal abre una ventana de diálogo para insertar un
      nombre.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial3 para 4 -->
    
    <?float-clear?> 
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step10" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step10.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial3 para 5 --> 
    <para lang="en">
	    Clicking on a main category, opens up its subcategories. You select a subcategory
	    for mapping to the current transaction by simply clicking on it. In order to map a
	    main category, you have to call its context menu.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Cliquez sur une catégorie principale pour ouvrir ses sous-catégories. Vous pouvez
      sélectionner une sous-catégorie pour l'opération en cours en cliquant simplement
      dessus. Si vous voulez utiliser la catégorie principale, il vous faudra passer par
      le menu contextuel.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Ein Klick auf eine Hauptkategorie öffnet die Liste der Unterkategorien. Die
      Zuordnung einer Unterkategorie zur aktuellen Buchung erfolgt durch kurzen Klick. Die
      Zuordnung einer Hauptkategorie ist durch das Kontextmenü möglich.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Cliccando su una categoria principale, apre le sue sottocategorie. Si seleziona una
      sottocategoria per la transazione corrente, semplicemente cliccando. Al fine di mappare
      un categoria principale, si deve chiamare il suo menù contestuale. 
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Un clic sobre una categoría principal abre la lista de subcategorías. La asignación de
      una subcategoría a un asiento actual se realiza a través de un breve clic. La asignación
      de una categoría principal es posible a través del menú contextual.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial3 para 5 --> 
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial3 para 6 --> 
    <para lang="en">
	    From here you can also add new subcategories, delete a category or edit it.
	    Subcategories have also context menus for deleting and editing.
	  </para>
    <para lang="fr">
	    A partir de là, vous pouvez ajouter de nouvelles sous-catégories, effacer ou
	    modifier une catégorie principale. Les sous-catégories ont aussi un menu contextuel
	    afin de les effacer ou de les modifier.
	  </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Dieses erlaubt auch das Anlegen neuer Unterkategorien, das Löschen und das Verändern
      einer Hauptkategorie. Die Unterkategorien verfügen auch über ein Kontextmenü mit
      Einträgen zum Löschen und Verändern.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Da qui è inoltre possibile aggiungere nuove sottocategorie, eliminare una categoria o
      modificarlo. Sottocategorie hanno anche menù di scelta rapida per la eliminazione e la
      modifica.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Este menú permite también crear nuevas subcategorías, y borrar y modificar categorías
      principales. También las subcategorías disponen de un menú contextual para borrar- o
      modificarlas.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial3 para 6 --> 
  </sect1>
   
   <!-- Tutorial4 -->
  <sect1 id="tutorial4">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para lang="en">
          How to export transactions
        </para>
        <para lang="fr">
          Commment exporter les opérations
        </para>
        <para lang="de">
          Wie man Kategorien verwaltet
        </para>
        <para lang="it">
          Como esportare gli operazioni
        </para>
        <para lang="es">
          Cómo exportar asientos
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info> 
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Export transactions</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Exporter les opérations</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Buchungen exportieren</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Esportazione di operazioni</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Exportar asientos</phrase>
    </title>
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step11" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step11.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial4 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      Finally, the raison d'être of <application role="app_name"/> is its support
      for export into QIF format. Call this function through the
      <guibutton role="menu_reset"/> button from the transaction list. This will
      create a file on your sdcard with all transactions for the current account, delete
      them from the database, and adjust the opening balance to the last current balance.
      <application role="app_name"/> can share the file immediately after the export through
      FTP, email or any other file sharing app, as explained in <link linkend='tutorial5_3'
        ><guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/></link>.
      <phrase role="br"/>
      Transfer operations will also be deleted from the account, but still be visible in
      the other account they refer to.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      La raison d'être de <application role="app_name"/> est de permettre
      l'exportation vers un fichier de format QIF. Vous pouvez lancer cette fonction par
      le bouton <guibutton role="menu_reset"/> dans la liste des opérations.
      Ceci va créer un fichier sur votre carte SD avec toutes les opérations du compte en
      cours, les enlever de la base de données et ajuster le solde initial avec le solde
      courant. Ce fichier peut être transféré par FTP, courriel ou d'autres applications comme
      expliqué dans <link linkend='tutorial5_3'><guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"
        /></link>. 
      <phrase role="br"/>
      Les opérations de virement seront aussi enlevées du compte mais resteront visibles
      dans l'autre compte concerné.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Die Grundmotivation für <application role="app_name"/> ist der Export in eine
      QIF Datei. Diese Funktion wird durch den Schaltknopf
      <guibutton role="menu_reset"/> von der Buchungsliste aus aufgerufen.
      Hiedurch wird eine Datei auf der SD-Karte erzeugt, die alle Buchungen des aktuellen
      Kontos enthält. Diese werden gelöscht und der aktuelle Saldo wird in den neuen
      Anfangssaldo übertragen. Sofort nach dem Export kann die Datei weitergeleitet
      werden, mittels FTP, Email oder anderen Apps, die Dateien übertragen können (siehe <link
        linkend='tutorial5_3'><guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/></link>).
      <phrase role="br"/>
      Umbuchungen werden auch von dem Konto gelöscht, sind aber im anderen Konto, auf das
      sie sich beziehen, weiterhin sichtbar.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Infine, la ragion d'essere di <application role="app_name"/> è il suo supporto per
      l'esportazione in formato QIF. Chiama questa funzione attraverso la voce <guibutton
      role="menu_reset"/> di menù dalla lista transazione. Questo sarà crea un file sul tuo
      scheda SD con tutte le transazioni per il conto corrente, eliminare dal database, e
      regolare il saldo di apertura con il saldo corrente. <application role="app_name"/> posso
      condividere il file subito dopo il export, sia caricarlo in un server FTP, inviarla via
      e-mail o altra applicazione come spiegato in <link linkend='tutorial5_3'>
      <guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/></link>).
      <phrase role="br"/>
      Operazioni di trasferimento verrà eliminato anche dal conto, ma ancora visibile in
      l'altro conto a cui si riferiscono.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      La motivación básica para <application role="app_name"/> es exportar a un archivo QIF. Esta 
      función se inicia desde la lista de asientos a través del botón <guibutton role="menu_reset"/>. 
      De esta manera se crea en la tarjeta SD un archivo que contiene todos los asientos de la cuenta 
      actual.Éstos son eliminados y el saldo actual es transferido al nuevo saldo inicial. 
      Inmediatamete después de la exportación se puede enviar el archivo, vía FTP, correo electrónico 
      o otras aplicaciones que pueden transferir archivos (vease <link linkend='tutorial5_3'><guilabel 
        role="pref_perform_share_title"/></link>).
      <phrase role="br"/>
      Traspasos también son eliminados de la cuenta, pero quedan visibles en la otra cuenta a la que
      se refieren.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial4 para 1 --> 
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial4 para 2 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      Voilà. You can now connect your phone to your computer, open Grisbi (or Gnucash),
      and use its import functionality.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Voilà. Maintenant, vous pouvez connecter votre téléphone à votre ordinateur, ouvrir
      Grisbi (ou Gnucash) et utiliser sa fonction d'importation.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Voilà. Jetzt können Sie Ihr Telefon mit dem Computer verbinden, Grisbi (oder
      Gnucash) öffnen und seine Import-Funktion verwenden.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Voilà. È ora possibile collegare il telefono al computer, aprire Grisbi (o GnuCash),
      e utilizzare la funzionalità di importazione.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Voilà. Ahora usted puede conectar su teléfono al ordenador, abrir Grisbi (o Gnucash) y
      utilizar su función de importación.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial4 para 2 -->  
  </sect1>

   <!-- Tutorial5 -->
  <sect1 id="tutorial5">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para lang="en">
          How to configure <application role="app_name"/>
        </para>
        <para lang="fr">
          Commment configurer <application role="app_name"/>
        </para>
        <para lang="de">
          Wie man <application role="app_name"/> konfiguriert
        </para>
        <para lang="it">
          Como configurare
        </para>
        <para lang="es">
          Cómo configurar <application role="app_name"/>
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info> 
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Settings</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Paramètres</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Einstellungen</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Parametri</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Configuraciones</phrase>
    </title>
    
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step12" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step12.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      A short click on the <guibutton role="menu_settings"/> button opens the preferences
      screen, from where you can configure some properties of <application role="app_name"/>,
      and also have access to the account management, and to the backup functionality. A
      long click opens up a menu with shortcuts to the configuration of the current
      account and to the backup.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Un clic court sur le bouton <guibutton role="menu_settings"/> ouvre l'écran des
      paramètres. Ici vous pouvez configurer quelques propriétés de <application
      role="app_name"/> et pouvez accéder à la gestion des comptes, ainsi qu'à la sauvegarde.
      Un clic long ouvre un menu qui comporte l'accès direct à la configuration du compte en
      cours, ainsi qu'à la sauvegarde.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Ein kurzer Klick auf den Schaltknopf <guibutton role="menu_settings"/> öffnet den
      Einstellungs-Bildschirm. Hier können sie einige Eigenschaften von <application
      role="app_name"/> konfigurieren, und haben auch Zugriff auf die Kontoverwaltung und
      die Backup-Funktion. Ein langer Klick öffnet ein Menü mit schnellem Zugriff auf die
      Konfiguration des aktuellen Kontos, sowie aufs Backup.    
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Un breve clic sul pulsante <guibutton role="menu_settings"/> si apre la schermata
      parametri. Qui è possibile impostare alcune proprietà di applicazione <application
      role="app_name"/> può accedere alla gestione degli account e di backup. Un clic lungo si
      apre un menu che include l'accesso diretto al conto attuale (<guimenuitem
      role="menu_settings_account"/>), e di backup (<guimenuitem role="menu_backup"/>).
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
    	Un rápido clic en el botón <guibutton role="menu_settings"/> abre la pantalla para la
    	configuración. Aquí usted puede configurar algunas de las propiedades de <application
    	role="app_name"/> y tiene también acceso a la administración de cuentas y a la función de
    	backup. Un clic largo abre un menú que comprende el acceso rápido a la configuración de
    	la cuenta actual y al backup.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial5 para 1 --> 
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_1">
    <title>
       <guilabel role="pref_manage_accounts_title"/>
    </title>
      
      <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_1 para 1 --> 
      <para lang="en">
        Here you see the complete account list. Clicking
        on an item, opens up the configuration form (explained in <link
        linkend="tutorial1" endterm="tutorial1.title"/>). A long click on the account
        brings up the context menu, from where you can delete the account, unless it is
        the current account that cannot be deleted.
      </para>
      <para lang="fr">
        Ici s'affiche la liste complète des comptes. En cliquant
        sur un compte, vous accédez au formulaire de configuration (expliqué dans <link
        linkend="tutorial1" endterm="tutorial1.title"/>). Un clic long affiche un menu
        contextuel permettant d'effacer le compte, à l'exception du compte en cours, qui
        ne peut pas être effacé.
      </para>
      <para lang="de">
        Hier wird eine komplette Liste der Konten angezeigt. Durch den
        Klick auf ein Konto wird das Konfigurationsformular geöffnet (erklärt in <link
        linkend="tutorial1" endterm="tutorial1.title"/>). Ein langer Klick bringt das
        Kontextmenü zum Vorschein, mit der Möglichkeit, das Konto zu löschen, mit der
        Ausnahme des aktuellen Kontos, das nicht gelöscht werden kann.
      </para>
      <para lang="it">
        Questo mostra l'elenco completo dei conti. Facendo clic sul conto, accedere al modulo
        di installazione (spiegato nel <link linkend="tutorial1" endterm="tutorial1.title"/>).
        Un clic lungo visualizza un menu di scelta rapida per cancellare conti, ad eccezione
        del conto corrente, che non possono essere cancellati.
      </para>
      <para lang="es">
        Aquí se muestra una lista completa de las cuentas. Al hacer clic en una cuenta se abre
        el formulario de configuración (como se explica en <link linkend="tutorial1"
        endterm="tutorial1.title"/>). Por medio de un clic largo se abre el menú de contexto
        que permite eliminar la cuenta, exceptuando la cuenta actual que no puede ser
        eliminada.
      </para>
      <!-- END tutorial5_1 para 1 --> 

    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="tutorial5_2">
      <title>
       <guilabel role="pref_categories_sort_by_usages_title"/>
      </title>
      
      <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_2 para 1 --> 
      <para lang="en">
        By default, categories are sorted primarily by how often you associate them with your
        transactions. Uncheck this option if you want your categories being sorted in
        alphabetical order instead.
      </para>
      <para lang="fr">
        Par défaut, les catégories sont triées par fréquence d'utilisation ( nombre de fois où
        vous les associez à une transaction). Décochez cette option si vous préferez que les
        catégories s'affichent par ordre alphabétique.
      </para>
      <para lang="de">
        Standardmäßig werden die Kategorien anhand der Benützungshäufigkeit sortiert (wie oft
        werden sie einer Buchung zugeordnet). Entfernen Sie das Häckchen von dieser Option,
        wenn Sie möchten, dass die Kategorien immer in alphabetischer Reihenfolge aufgelistet
        werden.
      </para>
      <para lang="it">
        Per impostazione predefinita, le categorie sono ordinati per frequenza di utilizzo
        (numero di volte che sono normalmente associati con una transazione). Deselezionare
        questa opzione se si preferisce che le categorie sono visualizzate in ordine
        alfabetico.
      </para>
      <para lang="es">
        De forma predeterminada las categorías son ordenadas segun la frecuencia de uso (la
        frecuencia con que son asignadas a un asiento.) Quite la marca de esta opción si desea
        que las categorías se muestren siempre en orden alfabético.
      </para>
      <!-- END tutorial5_2 para 1 --> 
      
    </sect2>
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_3">
      <title>
       <guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/>
      </title>
      
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_3 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      If you check this option, each time you export your transactions, your QIF file will be
      sent to a remote destination. Under <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/> you
      specify the destination:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An URL to a directory on an FTP server, you have write access to (e.g.
            "ftp://login:password@my.example.org:port/my/directory/"). If available on your device, 
            <application role="app_name"/> will launch an external app responding to a SENDTO intent
            with this URL as data. Only know app handling such an intent is
              <ulink url="market://details?id=org.totschnig.sendwithftp"><application>Send With FTP</application></ulink>
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An Email URL (e.g. "mailto:john@my.example.com"). <application role="app_name"/>
            will launch an email application and create a message to that address with the file
            attached to it.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            You can also leave this field empty, and you will be presented with a chooser
            allowing you to select one of your installed apps that allow sharing of files (e.g. 
            Dropbox, Google Docs, &#8230;).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Si vous cochez cette option, le fichier QIF sera téléchargé après chaque export de vos
      transactions. Sous <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/>, vous spécifiez la
      destination:
       <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            L'URL d'un dossier accessible par FTP en mode écriture (par exemple
            "ftp://login:password@my.example.org:port/my/directory/").
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          Un URL de courriel (par exemple "mailto:john@my.example.com"). Votre application de
          courriel sera lancé avec un nouveau message comportant le fichier en pièce jointe.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          Si ce champ reste vide, vous pourrez chaque fois choisir entre les apps disponibles
          sur votre appareil, capable de transférer un fichier (par exemple Dropbox, Google
          Docs, &#8230;).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Kreuzen Sie diese Option an, wenn Sie die QIF Datei nach dem Export Ihrer Buchungen an
      eine entfernte Adresse übertragen wollen. Unter <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"
        /> können Sie das Ziel konfigurieren:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
           Die URL eines Ordners, auf den Sie über FTP Schreibzugriff haben (z.B. 
           "ftp://login:password@my.example.org:port/my/directory/").
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Eine Email URL (z.B. "mailto:john@my.example.com"). Ihre Email-Anwendung wird
            gestartet, und eine Email erzeugt mit der Datei als Anhang.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          Sie können dieses Feld auch leer lassen, dann können Sie jedesmal zwischen auf Ihrem
          Gerät installierten Apps wählen, die Dateien übertragen können (z.B Dropbox, Google
          Docs, &#8230;).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Se si seleziona questa opzione, il file QIF verrà caricato dopo ogni esportare i vostri 
      transazioni. Sotto <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/>, è necessario specificare 
      la destinazione:
       <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          L'URL di un file tramite FTP in modalità di scrittura (ad esempio
          "ftp://login:password@my.example.org:port/my/directory/").
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          un URL per email (ad esempio "mailto:john@my.example.com"). Il vostro applicazione 
	  di posta elettronica si aprirà con un nuovo messaggio con il file allegato.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          Se questo campo è vuoto, è possibile scegliere ogni volta che le applicazioni disponibili 
	  sul dispositivo, in grado di trasferire un file (ad esempio, Dropbox, Google docs, &#8230;).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Marque esta opción si después de exportar sus asientos quiere transferir el archivo QIF a
      una dirección remota. Bajo <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/> puede configurar la
      meta:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            La URL de una carpeta a la que tiene acceso de escritura a través de FTP (por
            ejemplo, "ftp://login:password@my.example.org:port/my/directory/").
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Una dirección URL para correo electrónico (por ejemplo,
            "mailto:john@my.example.com").Se pone en marcha su aplicación de correo electrónico
            y se genera un correo electrónico con el archivo adjunto.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            También puede dejar este campo en blanco, entonces siempre puede elegir entre las
            aplicaciones para transferir archivos que estén instaladas en su aparato (como
            Dropbox, Google Docs, &#8230;).
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>      
    <!-- END tutorial5_3 para 1 --> 
  </sect2>
    
  <sect2 id="tutorial5_4">
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Backup and restore</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Sauvegarde et restauration</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Backup und Wiederherstellung</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Backup e ripristino</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Backup y Restauración</phrase>
    </title>
    
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_4 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      <guilabel role="menu_backup"/> creates a backup of database and preferences in
      the <filename>myexpenses</filename> folder on the sdcard. The database is stored in
      a file named <filename>BACKUP</filename>, the preferences in a file named
      <filename>BACKUP_PREF</filename>. Both are automatically restored when you reinstall
      <application role="app_name"/>. Thus you can retrieve all your application
      data on a different device by copying these two files into the same location there,
      before installing <application role="app_name"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      <guilabel role="menu_backup"/> créé une sauvegarde de la base de données et
      des préférences dans le répertoire <filename>myexpenses</filename> de la carte SD.
      La base de données est stockée dans le fichier <filename>BACKUP</filename> et les
      préférences dans <filename>BACKUP_PREF</filename>. Ceux-ci sont automatiquement
      restaurés lorsque vous réinstallez <application role="app_name"/>. Ainsi,
      vous pouvez récupérez toutes vos données sur un périphérique différent en copiant
      ces deux fichiers au même endroit avant d'installer
      <application role="app_name"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      <guilabel role="menu_backup"/> erzeugt eine Sicherungskopie von Datenbank und
      Einstellungen im <filename>myexpenses</filename> Ordner auf der SD-Karte. Die
      Datenbank wird in der Datei <filename>BACKUP</filename> gespeichert, die
      Einstellungen in der Datei <filename>BACKUP_PREF</filename>. Beide werden
      automatisch wiederhergestellt, wenn <application role="app_name"/> neu
      installiert wird. Sie können also die Anwendungsdaten komplett auf ein weiteres
      Gerät kopieren, indem Sie diese beiden Dateien an denselben Ort auf diesem kopieren,
      bevor Sie <application role="app_name"/> installieren.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      <guilabel role="menu_backup"/> crea un backup del database e delle preferenze nella
      cartella <filename>myexpenses</filename> sulla scheda SD. Il database viene memorizzato
      nel file chiamato <filename>BACKUP</filename> e le preferenze nel file
      <filename>BACKUP_PREF</filename>. Entrambi sono automaticamente ripristinate quando si
      reinstalla <application role="app_name"/>. In questo modo è possibile recuperare tutte le
      vostre applicazioni dati su un dispositivo diverso da copiare questi due file nella
      stessa posizione là, prima di installare <application role="app_name"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      <guilabel role="menu_backup"/> crea una copia de seguridad de la base de datos y de las
      configuraciones en el archivo <filename>myexpenses</filename> en la tarjeta SD. La base
      de datos se guarda en el archivo <filename>BACKUP</filename>, las configuraciones en el
      archivo <filename>BACKUP_PREF</filename>. Ambos se restauran automáticamente al volver a
      instalarse <application role="app_name"/>. Así que usted puede copiar los enteros datos
      de aplicación a otro aparato copiando estos dos archivos al mismo lugar antes de instalar
      <application role="app_name"/>.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial5_4 para 1 --> 
    </sect2>
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_5">
      <title>
        <guilabel role="pref_import_from_grisbi_title"/>
      </title>

    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step7" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step7.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>

    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_5 para 1 -->   
    <para lang="en">
    	This entry allows to set up categories from files included from Grisbi in English, German
    	or French. If with Grisbi you have already defined your own categories, you can also
    	provide your Grisbi file, which is in XML. If you want, you can edit the file with an
    	editor and remove any information other than the <sgmltag>Category</sgmltag> and
    	<sgmltag>Sub_category</sgmltag> elements<footnote id="ftn55-en-1">
	      <para>
	        <application role="app_name"/> also supports the Grisbi file format 0.5.0, where the
	        elements are named <sgmltag>Categorie</sgmltag> and <sgmltag>Sous_categorie</sgmltag>
	        (<sgmltag>Tiers</sgmltag> for parties).
	      </para>
	    </footnote>. Store this file as <filename role="grisbi_file"/> in a folder
	    <filename>myexpenses</filename> in the root of your sdcard<footnote id="ftn55-en-2">
	      <para>
	        Of course you can also create an XML file by your own. You can find the examples at
	        <ulink url="https://github.com/mtotschnig/MyExpenses/tree/master/res/raw">Github</ulink>.
	      </para>
	    </footnote>. You can
	    also import the parties (payers and payees) stored in this file (element
	    <sgmltag>Party</sgmltag>). When you choose your custom file as import source, you can
	    decide to import both parties and categories, or only categories. Partners will be used
	    for the autocomplete function of the payer/payee field in the transaction form.
    </para>   
    <para lang="fr">
	    Cette entrée vous permet de les entrer directement à partir des définitions standards de
	    Grisbi en anglais, allemand ou français. Si vous aviez déjà défini vos propres
	    catégories, vous pouvez aussi utiliser votre fichier Grisbi qui est en format XML. Dans
	    ce cas, copiez votre fichier et enlevez toutes les informations autres que les blocs de
	    catégories (<sgmltag>Category</sgmltag>) et de sous-catégories
	    (<sgmltag>Sub_category</sgmltag>)<footnote id="ftn55-fr-1">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> supporte aussi la version 0.5.0 du format de fichier
          Grisbi, où les éléments portent les noms <sgmltag>Categorie</sgmltag> et
          <sgmltag>Sous_categorie</sgmltag> ((<sgmltag>Tiers</sgmltag> pour les tiers)).
        </para>
	    </footnote>. Sauvegardez ce fichier sous le nom <filename role="grisbi_file"/> dans le
	    répertoire <filename>myexpenses</filename> de la racine de votre carte SD<footnote id="ftn55-fr-2">
	      <para>
	        Bien sûr, vous pouvez aussi créer vous-même un fichier XML. Vous trouveriez des exemples chez
	        <ulink url="https://github.com/mtotschnig/MyExpenses/tree/master/res/raw">Github</ulink>.
	      </para>
	    </footnote>.
	    Vous avez aussi l'option d'importer les tiers que Grisbi enregistre dans
	    le même fichier (élément <sgmltag>Party</sgmltag>). Si vous choississez votre propre
	    fichier en tant que source de l'import, vous pourrez soit importer tiers et catégories,
	    soit uniquement les catégories. Les tiers vous seront proposés pour remplir
	    automatiquement le champ "tiers" dans le formulaire des opérations.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Dieser Eintrag erlaubt die in Grisbi definierten Kategorien (Englisch, Deutsch oder
      Französisch) zu importieren. Sie können auch eine Grisbi Datei (in XML) verwenden, die
      Ihre eigenen Kategorien enthält. Sie können diese Datei editieren und alle Informationen
      außer die Elemente <sgmltag>Category</sgmltag> und <sgmltag>Sub_category</sgmltag>
      entfernen<footnote id="ftn55-de-1">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> unterstützt auch das Grisbi Datei Format 0.5.0, in dem
          die Elemente <sgmltag>Categorie</sgmltag> und <sgmltag>Sous_categorie</sgmltag>
          heißen (<sgmltag>Tiers</sgmltag> für Parteien).
        </para>
      </footnote>. Kopieren Sie diese Datei unter dem Namen
      <filename role="grisbi_file"/> in einen Ordner <filename>myexpenses</filename> in das
      Wurzelverzeichnis der SD-Karte<footnote id="ftn55-de-2">
        <para>
          Natürlich können Sie auch Ihre eigene XML Datei erzeugen. Sie finden Beispiele dafür auf
          <ulink url="https://github.com/mtotschnig/MyExpenses/tree/master/res/raw">Github</ulink>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Sie können zusätzlich auch die von
      Grisbi gespeicherten Parteien (Empfänger und Zahler), aus dieser Datei importieren
      (Element <sgmltag>Party</sgmltag>). Wenn Sie Ihre eigene Datei als Import-Quelle
      auswählen, können Sie entweder Parteien und Kategorien oder nur Kategorien importieren.
      Die Partner werden im Buchungsformular verwendet, um Ihnen für das Feld Empfänger/Zahler
      ein automatische Ausfüllen vorzuschlagen.
    </para>   
    <para lang="it">
      <guibutton role="import_categories"/> permette di impostare le categorie di file inclusa
      da Grisbi in inglese, tedesco o francese. Se con Grisbi hai già definite le proprie
      categorie, è possibile anche fornire il file Grisbi, che è in XML. Se si desidera, è
      possibile modificare il file con un editor e rimuovere ogni altra informazione rispetto
      alla categoria (<sgmltag>Category</sgmltag>) e gli elementi
      <sgmltag>Sub_category</sgmltag><footnote id="ftn55-it-1">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> supporta anche il formato di file Grisbi 0.5.0, dove
          gli elementi sono denominati <sgmltag>Categorie</sgmltag> e
          <sgmltag>Sous_categorie</sgmltag>(<sgmltag>Tiers</sgmltag> beneficiari).
        </para>
      </footnote>. Conservare questo file come <filename role="grisbi_file"/> in un
      <filename>myexpenses</filename> cartella nella directory principale della vostra scheda
      SD<footnote id="ftn55-it-2">
        <para>
          Certamente può sviluppare il suo proprio xml file. Esempi per questo si trovano qui
          <ulink url="https://github.com/mtotschnig/MyExpenses/tree/master/res/raw">Github</ulink>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Hai anche la possibilità di importare i beneficiari Grisbi
      registrati nello stesso file (elemento <sgmltag>Party</sgmltag>). Se si sceglie il
      proprio file come fonte di importazione, è possibile importare categorie e beneficiari, o
      solo categorie. Il beneficiario sarà offerta automaticamente per riempire il
      "Beneficiario" in forma di operazioni.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Esta entrada permite importar categorías definidas en Grisbi (inglés, alemán y francés).
      Puede usar también un archivo de Grisbi (en XML) que contiene sus propias categorías.
      Puede editar este archivo y eliminar todas las informaciones excepto los elementos
      <sgmltag>Category</sgmltag> y <sgmltag>Sub_category</sgmltag><footnote id="ftn55-es-1">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> apoya también el formato de archivos Grisbi 0.5.0. en
          el que los elementos se llaman <sgmltag>Categorie</sgmltag> y
          <sgmltag>Sous_categorie</sgmltag> (<sgmltag>Tiers</sgmltag> para partes).
        </para>
      </footnote>. Copie este archivo bajo el nombre <filename role="grisbi_file"/> a una
      carpeta <filename>myexpenses</filename> en el directorio raíz de la tarjeta SD<footnote id="ftn55-es-2">
        <para>
          Por supuesto, usted puede también crear su propio archivo XML. Puede encontrar ejemplos en
          <ulink url="https://github.com/mtotschnig/MyExpenses/tree/master/res/raw">Github</ulink>.
        </para>
      </footnote>.
      Puede importar de este archivo además los partes (receptores y
      pagadores) guardados en Grisbi (elemento <sgmltag>Party</sgmltag>). Si elige su propio
      archivo como fuente de importación, puede importar partes y categorías o sólo
      categorías. Los partes se utilizan en el formulario de asientos para proponerle un
      llenado automático en el campo receptor/pagador.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial5_5 para 1 --> 
    </sect2>
        
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_6">
      <title>
        <guilabel role="pref_use_standard_menu_title"/>
      </title>
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_6 para 1 --> 
    <para lang="en">
      If this option is checked, Android's standard menu will be used in the transaction list
      for accessing commands instead of displaying a button bar. You will be offered to
      activate the menu based interface when clicking on the hardware menu button.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Si vous cochez cette option, au lieu d'afficher une barre de boutons, vous utiliserez le
      menu standard d'Android pour accéder aux commandes. Vous pouvez aussi accéder au
      changement de configuration simplement en activant le bouton Menu hardware.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Indem Sie diese Option anklicken, können Sie anstatt der Symbolleiste Androids
      Standardmenü verwenden, um Befehle auszuführen. Sie können diesen Parameter auch durch
      Drücken des Hardware Menüknopfes verändern.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
       Se si seleziona questa opzione, invece di visualizzare una barra dei pulsanti, sarà
       necessario utilizzare il menu standard per accedere al Android ordini. È inoltre
       possibile accedere alla modifica della configurazione semplicemente attivando il
       pulsante Menu hardware.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Al hacer clic en esta opción puede utilizar el menú estándar de Android, en lugar de la
      barra de símbolos, para ejecutar mandos. Puede cambiar este parámetro también pulsando el
      botón hardware dedicado al menú.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial5_6 para 1 --> 
  </sect2>
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_7">
      <title>
        <guilabel role="pref_manage_parties_title"/>
      </title>
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_7 para 1 -->
    <para lang="en">
      This screen lists the parties used for the autocompletion of the <guilabel
      role="payer"/>/<guilabel role="payee"/> field. You can remove entries from this list, by
      checking the checkbox on their right side, and then clicking on the <guibutton
      role="menu_delete"/> button.
    </para>
    
    <para lang="fr">
      Sur cet écran s'affiche la liste des tiers utilisés pour le complément automatique du
      champ <guilabel role="payer"/>. Pour supprimer des entrées de cette liste,
      sélectionnez-les en cochant à leur droite, et activez ensuite le bouton <guibutton
      role="menu_delete"/>.
    </para>
    
    <para lang="de">
      Auf diesem Bildschirm wird die Liste der Parteien angezeigt, die für die automatische
      Komplettierung des Feldes <guilabel role="payer"/>/<guilabel role="payee"/> verwendet
      wird. Sie können Einträge aus dieser Liste entfernen, indem Sie das Markierungsfeld in
      der jeweiligen Zeile ankreuzen, und dann den Schaltknopf <guibutton role="menu_delete"/>
      betätigen.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Su questo schermo l'elenco dei terzi utilizzato per il completamento automatico del campo
      <guilabel role="payer"/>/<guilabel role="payee"/>. Per rimuovere le voci da questo
      elenco, selezionarle controllando il loro diritto, e quindi attivare il pulsante
      <guibutton role="menu_delete"/>.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      En esta pantalla aparece la lista de las partes que se usa para el llenado automático del
      campo pagador/receptor. Para eliminar elementos de esta lista marque la casilla en el
      renglón correspondiente y pulse el botón eliminar.
    </para>
     <!-- END tutorial5_7 para 1 --> 
    </sect2>
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_8">
      <title>
        <guilabel role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_title"/>
      </title>
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_8 para 1 -->
    <para lang="en">
      By default, currency amounts for transactions (or the opening balance of an account) use
      the decimal separator of your locale (comma in most European countries, point in most
      English speaking countries)<footnote id="ftn58-en-2">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> uses the point symbol (.) as default on devices
          running Android 2.3, since those are most heavily affected by the problem described
          in the <link linkend='faq-comma-en'>FAQ</link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>, here you can explicitly configure it.
      Alternatively you have the option to input minor units (e.g. $ cents, € cent, or £ pence)
      as integers.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Par défaut, les montants de transactions (ou le solde d'ouverture d'un compte) utilisent
      le séparateur décimal de votre région (virgule dans les pays européens, point dans les
      pays anglophones)<footnote id="ftn58-fr-2">
        <para>
          Sur les appareils sous Android 2.3., <application role="app_name"/> utilise par
          défaut le point, car ceux-ci sont le plus souvent concerné par le problème décrit
          dans la <link linkend='faq-comma-fr'>FAQ</link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>, ici vous pouvez le configurer explicitement. Sinon, vous avez la
      possibilité d'entrer des unités mineures entières (par exemple $ cents, centimes d' €,
      pence pour £).
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Standardmäßig wird für Währungsbeträge in Buchungen (oder das Anfangssaldo eines Kontos)
      das Dezimaltrennzeichen Ihrer Spracheinstellung verwendet (Komma in den meisten
      europäischen Ländern, Punkt in den meisten englischsprachigen Ländern)<footnote id="ftn58-de-2">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> verwendet auf Geräten mit Android 2.3. als Standard
          den Punkt, da diese am meisten von dem in der <link linkend='faq-comma-de'>FAQ</link>
          beschriebenen Problem betroffen sind.
        </para>
      </footnote>, hier kann dieses
      explizit konfiguriert werden. Sie können hier aber auch festlegen, dass Sie
      Untereinheiten (z.B $ Cents, € Cent, oder £ Pence) als ganze Zahlen eingeben.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Per impostazione predefinita, gli importi delle transazioni (o il saldo di
      apertura di un conto) utilizzare il separatore decimale delle impostazioni locali
      (virgola in molti paesi europei, il punto in più paesi di lingua inglese)<footnote
      id="ftn58-it-2">
        <para>
          Sui dispositivi con sistema operativo Android 2.3., <application role="app_name"/>,
          il default è il punto, perché sono per lo più si occupano del problema descritto
          nella <link linkend='faq-comma-it'>FAQ</link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>, qui si può configurare in modo esplicito. In alternativa si ha la
      possibilità di ingresso alle unità minori (es. $ centesimi, € cent o penny £) come interi
      (<guilabel role="pref_currency_decimal_separator_input_minor_unit"/>).
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Para valores de moneda en asientos (o en el saldo inicial de una cuenta) se usa de manera
      predeterminada el separador decimal de su configuración regional (coma en la mayoría de
      países europeos, punto en la mayoría de países de habla inglesa)<footnote id="ftn58-es-2">
        <para>
          <application role="app_name"/> utiliza en aparatos con Android 2.3. como estándard el
          punto, por que son esos los aparatos mas afectados por el problema descrito en <link
            linkend='faq-comma-es'>FAQ</link>.
        </para>
      </footnote>. Aquí se lo puede
      configurar de manera explícita. Además aquí se puede especificar que subunidades (por
      ejemplo US $ centavos, € céntimos o £ peniques ) se introducen como números
      enteros.
    </para>
      <!-- END tutorial5_8 para 1 --> 
    </sect2>
    
    <sect2 id="tutorial5_9">
    <title>
        <guilabel role="pref_manage_methods_title"/>
    </title>
    <figure floatstyle="left" id="step13" >
      <title/>
      <screenshot>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="step13.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </screenshot>
    </figure>
    <!-- BEGIN tutorial5_9 para 1 -->
    <para lang="en">
      This screen lists the predefined payment methods (Cheque,Credit card, Deposit, Direct debit) and
      lets you define new ones. Simply click on an entry (or select <guibutton role="menu_new"/>), 
      and you will enter a form, where you can define a label (unless for the predefined ones),
      and a type (is this method used for debit, income or both),
      and select the account types for which this method is applicable.
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
      Cet écran affiche la liste des méthodes de paiement prédéfinies (Chèque, Carte de crédit,
      Dépôt, Prélèvement) et vous permet d'en définir de nouvelles. En cliquant sur une entrée
      (ou en sélectionnant <guibutton role="menu_new"/>), vous ouvrez un formulaire pour définir un
      libellé (sauf pour les types prédéfinis) et le type (s'il s'agit d'une méthode de débit, de crédit
      ou neutre), et pour sélectionner les types de compte pour lesquels celle-ci est applicable.
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
      Auf diesem Bildschirm wird die Liste der vordefinierten Zahlungsweisen angezeigt (Scheck, Kreditkarte,
      Einzahlung, Abbuchung) und Sie können hier auch neue Zahlungsweisen definieren. Wenn Sie auf
      einen Eintrag in der Liste klicken (oder <guibutton role="menu_new"/> auswählen), gelangen Sie
      zu einem Formular, in dem Sie eine Bezeichnung (außer für die vordefinierten) und den Typ (handelt
      es sich um eine Zahlungsweise für Einnahmen, Ausgaben oder neutral) festlegen, und die Kontotypen
      auswählen, für die die Zahlungsweise anwendbar ist.
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
      Su questo schermo si vede la lista dei modi di pagamento predefiniti (assegno, carta di credito,
      pagamento, addebito) e qui puó definire nuovi modi di pagamento. Si fa clic su un modo della
      lista (o sceglie Nuovo), arriva a un formulario, dove può definire la descrizione (salvo per i 
      predefiniti) e il tipo (si tratta di un modo di pagamento per entrate o spese o neutrale), e 
      scegliere i tipi di conto per i quali è applicabile il modo di pagamento.
    </para>
    <para lang="es">
      Esta pantalla muestra la lista de los predefinidos métodos de pago (cheque, tarjeta de
      crédito, depósito, impuesto) y usted puede además definir nuevos métodos de pago. Al hacer
      clic en un elemento de la lista (o seleccionando <guibutton role="menu_new"/>) se llega a un
      formulario donde usted determina un nombre (excepto para los predefinidos) y el tipo (si se
      trata de un método de pago para ingresos, gastos o si es neutral) y elige los tipos de cuenta
      para los cuales el método de pago es aplicable.
    </para>
    <!-- END tutorial5_9 para 1 -->
    </sect2>
    
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="faq">
    <sect1info>
      <abstract>
        <para>
          FAQ 
        </para>
      </abstract>
    </sect1info>
    <title>
      <phrase lang="en">Frequently asked questions</phrase>
      <phrase lang="fr">Foire aux questions</phrase>
      <phrase lang="de">Häufig gestellte Fragen</phrase>
      <phrase lang="it">Domande più frequenti</phrase>
      <phrase lang="es">Preguntas más frecuentes</phrase>
    </title>
    <qandaset id="quandaset">
      <!-- BEGIN FAQ 1 -->
      <qandaentry id="faq-comma-en" lang="en">
        <question id="faq-comma-q-en">
          <para>
            How do I enter amounts? There is no comma (,) on the numeric keypad.
          </para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            There are different decimal separators used in different languages: comma in most
            European countries, point in most English speaking countries. Unfortunately there
            is a still unresolved problem in the Android OS, which does not handle the comma
            well in its numeric input method, and in some cases even does not allow at all to
            enter a comma. If you encounter this problem, you can set the point as decimal
            separator in the Settings.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-comma-fr" lang="fr">
        <question id="faq-comma-q-fr">
          <para>
            Comment puis-je saisir les montants ? Il n'y a pas de virgule (,) sur le pavé
            numérique.
          </para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Il existe différents séparateurs décimaux utilisés dans différentes langues:
            virgule dans la plupart des pays européens, le point dans les pays anglophones.
            Malheureusement, il existe un problème non encore résolu dans le système
            d'exploitation Android, il ne gère pas bien la virgule dans sa méthode d'entrée
            numérique, et dans certains cas ne permet même pas du tout d'entrer une virgule. Si
            vous rencontrez ce problème, vous pouvez définir le point comme séparateur décimal
            dans les paramètres.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-comma-de" lang="de">
        <question id="faq-comma-q-de">
          <para>
           Wie kann ich Beträge eingeben? Auf der numerischen Tastatur finde ich kein Komma
           (,).
          </para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            In den verschiedenen Sprachen werden unterschiedliche Dezimaltrennzeichen
            verwendet: Komma in den meisten europäischen Ländern, Punkt in den meisten
            englischsprachigen Ländern. Leider gibt es unter Android ein noch ungelöstes
            Problem, das die Verwendung des Kommas zur Eingabe von Dezimalzahlen erschwert, in
            manchen Fällen sogar unmöglich macht. Wenn Sie diesem Problem begegnen, können Sie
            in den Einstellungen den Punkt als Dezimaltrennzeichen festlegen.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-comma-it" lang="it">
        <question id="faq-comma-q-it">
          <para>
            Come faccio a inserire gli importi? Non c'è una virgola (,) sul tastierino numerico.
          </para>
          </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Ci sono diversi separatori decimali utilizzati nelle diverse lingue: virgola in
            molti paesi europei, il punto in più paesi di lingua inglese. Purtroppo c'è un
            problema ancora irrisolto nel sistema operativo Android, che non gestisce bene la
            virgola nel suo metodo di input numerico, e in alcuni casi addirittura non consente
            affatto di inserire una virgola. Se si verifica questo problema, è possibile
            impostare il punto come separatore decimale nelle Impostazioni.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-comma-es" lang="es">
        <question id="faq-comma-q-es">
          <para>
            ¿Cómo puedo insertar valores monitarios? No encuentro la coma (,) en el teclado.
          </para>
          </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            En las distintas lenguas se usan delimitadores decimales distintos: En la mayoría
            de los países europeos es la coma, en cambio se usa un punto en la mayoría de los
            países anglófonos. Desafortunadamente existe todavía un problema sin resolver, que
            complica el uso de la coma para la inserción de cifras decimales, y en algunos
            casos incluso lo imposibilita. Si usted da con este problema, puede determinar el
            punto como delimitador decimal en la configuración.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <!-- END FAQ 1 -->

      <!-- BEGIN FAQ 2 -->
      <qandaentry id="faq-share-de" lang="de">
        <question id="faq-share-q-de">
          <para>
            Kann ich die QIF Datei auf Google Docs oder Dropbox übertragen?
          </para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Ja, aktivieren Sie <guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/> in den
            Einstellungen, und lassen Sie <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/> leer. Dann
            können Sie nach jedem Export die App (wie z.B. Google Docs oder Dropbox) auswählen,
            mittels deren Sie die Datei übertragen wollen.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-share-en" lang="en">
        <question id="faq-share-q-en">
          <para>
            Can I send the QIF file to Google Docs or Dropbox?
          </para>
          </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Yes, in the settings, activate <guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/> and
            leave <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/> empty. After each export, you will
            see a chooser for selecting an app (like Google Docs or Dropbox) capable of sending
            the file.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-share-fr" lang="fr">
        <question id="faq-share-q-fr">
          <para>
            Puis-je envoyer le fichier QIF vers Google Docs ou Dropbox?
          </para>
          </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Oui, dans les paramètres, activez <guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/>, et
            gardez <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/> vide. Ainsi, après chaque export,
            vous pourrez choisir dans un menu une apps (par exemple Google Docs ou Dropbox)
            capable de transférer le fichier.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-share-it" lang="it">
        <question id="faq-share-q-it">
          <para>
            Posso inviare il file QIF di Google Docs o Dropbox?
          </para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Sì, nelle parametri, attivare <guilabel role="pref_perform_share_title"/>, e
            lasciare <guilabel role="pref_share_target_title"/> in bianco. Così, dopo ogni
            esportazione, è possibile scegliere da un menu un applicazioni (ad esempio Google
            Docs o Dropbox) in grado di trasferire il file.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>
      <qandaentry id="faq-share-es" lang="es">
        <question id="faq-share-q-es">
          <para>
            Puedo mover el archivo QIF a Google Docs o Dropbox?
          </para>
        </question>
        <answer>
          <para>
            Si, simplemente active en las configuraciones <guilabel
            role="pref_perform_share_title"/> y deje vacío la casilla <guilabel
            role="pref_share_target_title"/> . Así después de subir el archivo puede
            seleccionar la aplicación (por ejemplo Google Docs o Dropbox), con la cual quiere
            transmitir el archivo.
          </para>
        </answer>
      </qandaentry>   
    </qandaset>
  </sect1>

  <!--
template for new paragraphs
    <para lang="en">
    
    </para>
    <para lang="fr">
    
    </para>
    <para lang="de">
    
    </para>
    <para lang="it">
    
    </para>
    -->
  <!--
  template for FAQ entry
    <qandaentry id="" lang="">
      <question>
        <para>

        </para>
        </question>
      <answer>
        <para>

        </para>
      </answer>
   </qandaentry>
   -->
</article>
