<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <string name="help_menu_commands">Menu commands</string>

  <!-- My Expenses Transaction list -->
  <string name="help_MyExpenses_title">Transaction list</string>
  <string name="help_MyExpenses_info">This screen lists all transactions for the current account. From the
    navigation bar, you can navigate to the accounts list or select a different account.
    Click on a list entry to edit the item.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_transaction_help_text">Opens the form for creating a new transaction.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_transfer_help_text">Transfer money between accounts. This command is enabled
    only if you have at least one other account with the same currency as the current one.</string>
  <string name="menu_new_from_template_help_text">If you have created templates for the current account,
    this command displays a dialog for selecting a template from which a new transaction will be
    created.</string>
  <string name="menu_reset_help_text">This command will export all transactions of the current account to a file on
    the SD card in QIF or CSV format. By default, the transactions will be
    deleted from your phone, but you can select to keep them and mark as exported. My Expenses can share the
    file immediately after the export through FTP, email or any other file sharing app, if you configure it
    to do so in the Settings.</string>
  <string name="menu_edit_account_help_text">Adjust the properties of the current account
    (title, description, opening balance, account type, currency, color).</string>

  <!-- ManageAccounts Accounts list -->
  <string name="help_ManageAccounts_title">Accounts list</string>
  <string name="help_ManageAccounts_info">This screen lists all accounts. Clicking on a list entry, opens the
    transaction list for the account.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_account_help_text">Opens the form for creating a new account.</string>
  <string name="menu_aggregates_help_text">The aggregates dialog calculates the sum of expenses and income accross
    all accounts that share the same currency. The command is only available if for any currency there exist at
    least two accounts (Contrib feature).</string>
  <string name="menu_reset_all_help_text">This command allows to reset all your accounts in batch. It is not available
    if there are no transactions to export (Contrib feature).</string>

  <!-- ManageMethods title is in keys-->
  <string name="help_ManageMethods_info">This screen lists the predefined payment methods (Cheque,Credit card, Deposit,
    Direct debit) and lets you define new ones.
    Clicking on a list entry, lets you change the association between the method and account types.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_method_help_text">Opens the form for creating a new payment method.</string>

  <!-- ManageParties title is in keys -->
  <string name="help_ManageParties_info">This screen lists the parties used for the autocompletion of the Payer/Payee field.
    You can remove entries from this list through each entry\'s context menu.</string>

  <!-- ManageTemplates title is in keys-->
  <string name="help_ManageTemplates_info">This screen lists the the available templates grouped by account.
    While templates normally can be derived from transactions, here each account\'s context menu allows you to create
    new templates (for transactions or transfers). From a template\'s context menu you can instantiate it and either
    immediately save it or enter its editing form where you can modify it before saving. Clicking on an entry allows to
    modify it (Contrib feature).</string>

  <!-- SelectCategory title is in keys-->
  <string name="help_SelectCategory_info">This screen allows to create, edit and delete categories
    and when called from a transaction\'s edit form, to map the transaction to a selected category.
    By default, the primary sort criteria in the category list is the number of times you use a category
    (the secondary criteria is alphabetical order). This gives you quick access to the categories you use most often.
    In the settings, you can opt for sorting the categories in plain alphabetical order.
    Clicking on a main category, opens up its subcategories. You select a subcategory for mapping to the current
    transaction by simply clicking on it. In order to map a main category, you have to call its context menu.
    From here you can also add new subcategories, delete a category or edit it. Subcategories have also context
    menus for deleting and editing.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_main_cat_help_text">Opens the dialog for specifying the title of a new main category.</string>

  <!-- ExpenseEdit -->
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transaction_title">Form for transactions</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transfer_title">Form for transfers</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_template_title">Form for templates</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_split_title">Form for splits</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_splitPartTransaction_title">Form for category split parts</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_splitPartTransfer_title">Form for transfer split parts</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_info">Click on the - Button to toggle between expense and income, click on the = Button
    to open a calculator. The decimal separator for amounts can be configured in the settings.</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transaction_info">The payee (or payer)
    field remembers the values you enter and will suggest them in the future. The button for selecting a payment method,
    is only available if the current account is of a type linked to any payment method. By default only bank accounts, are 
    linked to payment methods (cheque,credit card, deposit,direct debit).</string>
  <string name="menu_save_help_text">Save the data and close the form.</string>
  <string name="menu_save_and_new_help_text">Save the data, leave the form open for creating a new transaction with the same
    data.</string>
  <!-- AccountEdit -->
    <string name="help_AccountEdit_title">Form for accounts</string>
    <string name="help_AccountEdit_info">The account is identified by its label, the description has only an informative purpose.
      The decimal separator for the opening balance can be configured in the settings. The currency must be entered according to
      its three-letter code in ISO 4217, but can be chosen easily from a list. You can
      define the type of an account as one of Cash, Bank, Asset, Liabilities, Credit Card. The type determines the available payment
      methods that you can configure under Settings -> Manage -> Payment Methods.</string>
  <!-- MethodEdit -->
  <string name="help_MethodEdit_title">Form for payment methods</string>
  <string name="help_MethodEdit_info">On this screen, you associate a payment method with account types.
     You can also define a label (with the exception of the predefined methods which have a fixed label that cannot be edited).
     Through a method\'s type, you determine if it is applicable for expenses (debit), income (credit) or both (neutral).</string>
</resources>