<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  This file is part of My Expenses.
  My Expenses is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  (at your option) any later version.

  My Expenses is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  GNU General Public License for more details.

  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with My Expenses.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
 -->
<resources>
  <string name="help_menu_commands">Menu commands</string>

  <!-- My Expenses Transaction list -->
  <string name="help_MyExpenses_title">Transaction list</string>
  <string name="help_MyExpenses_info">This screen lists all transactions for the current account. From the navigation bar, you can navigate to the accounts list or select a different account. Click on a list entry to edit the item.</string>
  <string name="help_MyExpenses_crStatus_info">The status of the transaction is indicated by a colored rectangle: gray for unreconciled, blue for clear, green for reconciled. Clicking on the rectangle, changes the status.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_transaction_help_text">Opens the form for creating a new transaction.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_transfer_help_text">Transfer money between accounts. This command is enabled only if you have at least one other account with the same currency as the current one.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_split_help_text">A split transaction allows you to assign partial amounts to different categories or as transfers to different accounts.</string>
  <string name="menu_reset_help_text">This command will export all transactions of the current account to a file on the SD card in QIF or CSV format. By default, the transactions will be deleted from your phone, but you can select to keep them and mark as exported. My Expenses can share the file immediately after the export through FTP, email or any other file sharing app, if you configure it to do so in the Settings.</string>
  <string name="menu_edit_account_help_text">Adjust the properties of the current account (title, description, opening balance, account type, currency, color).</string>
  <string name="menu_grouping_help_text">You can group transactions by day, week, month or year. For each group, the sum of income, expenses and transfers is calculated and displayed.</string>
  <string name="menu_distribution_help_text">Display the distribution of your expenses per category. You can also click on a group header to inspect the distribution for a specific group.</string>
  <string name="menu_manage_plans_help_text">Opens the list of templates and plans for the current account, where you can apply, edit or delete them, and also define plans for future and recurrent transactions.</string>

  <!-- ManageAccounts Accounts list -->
  <string name="help_ManageAccounts_title">Accounts list</string>
  <string name="help_ManageAccounts_info">This screen lists all accounts. Clicking on a list entry, opens the transaction list for the account.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_account_help_text">Opens the form for creating a new account.</string>
  <string name="menu_aggregates_help_text">The aggregates dialog calculates the sum of expenses and income across all accounts that share the same currency. The command is only available if for any currency there exist at least two accounts (Contrib feature).</string>
  <string name="menu_reset_all_help_text">This command allows to reset all your accounts in batch. It is not available if there are no transactions to export (Contrib feature).</string>

  <!-- ManageMethods title is in keys-->
  <string name="help_ManageMethods_info">This screen lists the predefined payment methods (Cheque, Credit card, Deposit, Direct debit) and lets you define new ones. Clicking on a list entry, lets you change the association between the method and account types.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_method_help_text">Opens the form for creating a new payment method.</string>

  <!-- ManageParties title is in keys -->
  <string name="help_ManageParties_info">This screen lists the parties used for the autocompletion of the Payer/Payee field. You can delete and edit parties through each entry\'s context menu.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_party_help_text">Opens the dialog for specifying the name of a new payer or payee.</string>
  
  <!-- ManageTemplates title is in keys-->
  <string name="help_ManageTemplates_info">This screen lists the available templates for the current account. While templates can be derived from transactions through their context menu, here you can create new templates from scratch (for transactions or transfers). From a template\'s context menu, you can instantiate the template and either save it immediately or enter its editing form where you can modify it before saving. The context menu also allows editing and deleting the template.&lt;h2>Plans&lt;/h2>Plans are listed on a separate tab. When you expand an entry, you will see the list of upcoming instances of a plan. Instead of waiting for the notification you receive when an instance occurs, here you can decide to apply these future occurences in advance in order to make them visible in your transaction list by calling the respective commands from the context menu. The state of an instance is indicated by the following icons:&lt;br>&lt;img src=\"ic_stat_open\" /&gt; The instance has not yet been applied.&lt;br>&lt;img src=\"ic_stat_applied\" /&gt; The instance has been applied.&lt;br>&lt;img src=\"ic_stat_cancelled\" /&gt; The instance has been cancelled, i.e. you have flaged it to be skipped. No transaction will be created for this instance.&lt;br>&lt;br>From the context menu, you can also reset an instance, which will delete a transaction if the instance has already been applied, or remove the cancelation flag.</string>  <string name="menu_create_template_for_transaction_help_text">Create a new template for a transaction</string>
  <string name="menu_create_template_for_transfer_help_text">Create a new template for a transfer</string>
  
  <!-- ManageCategories_* titles are in keys-->
  <string name="help_ManageCategories_distribution_info">This screen displays the distribution of your expenses and incomes per categories, for all transactions in an account, or for a specific group.</string>
  <string name="help_ManageCategories_select_info">In addition to the actions that you can perform when managing categories from the Preferences screen (create, edit, delete), on this screen you map a transaction to a selected category. You select a subcategory for mapping to the current transaction by simply clicking on it. In order to map a main category, you have to call its context menu.</string>
  <string name="help_ManageCategories_manage_info">This screen allows to create, edit and delete categories. By default, the primary sort criteria in the category list is the number of times you use a category (the secondary criteria is alphabetical order). This gives you quick access to the categories you use most often. In the settings, you can opt for sorting the categories in plain alphabetical order. Clicking on a main category, opens up its subcategories. From a main category\'s context menu, you can add new subcategories, delete a category or edit it. Subcategories have also context menus for deleting and editing.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_main_cat_help_text">Opens the dialog for specifying the title of a new main category.</string>
  <string name="menu_ManageCategories_distribution_grouping_help_text">Set the type of grouping and display the distribution per day, month, week or year.</string>
  <string name="menu_back_help_text">Navigate to the previous group. Can also be done through swipe gesture from left to right.</string>
  <string name="menu_forward_help_text">Navigate to the next group. Can also be done through swipe gesture from right to left.</string>

  <!-- ExpenseEdit -->
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transaction_title">Form for transactions</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transfer_title">Form for transfers</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_template_title">Form for templates</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_split_title">Form for splits</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_splitPartCategory_title">Form for category split parts</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_splitPartTransfer_title">Form for transfer split parts</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_info">Click on the = Button to open a calculator.</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transaction_info">Click on the - Button to toggle between expense and income. The payee (or payer) field remembers the values you enter and will suggest them in the future. The button for selecting a payment method, is only available if the current account is of a type linked to any payment method. By default only bank accounts, are  linked to payment methods (cheque,credit card, deposit,direct debit).</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_transfer_info">Select the transfer account from the drop down list.</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_template_info">Click on the - Button to toggle between expense and income. Enter a title that uniquely identifies the template.&lt;h2>Plans&lt;/h2>When you create a plan for a template, it is added to a private calendar handled by your Calendar app. You can define the plan as a one-time event or as any type of recurring event that the calendar can handle. You can create, modify and delete the plan from the plan button, but once the plan is set up, you can also use the Calendar app to manage it. A plan can be set to automatic or manual. When an instance of an automatic plan occurs, the transaction will be created, and you receive a notification. When the plan is manual, you also receive a notification, which leaves the choice of canceling, modifying or applying the template to you.</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_split_info">Enter as many split parts as needed through the menu commands for category splits and transfer splits. 	The bottom half of the screen displays the list of split parts and the amount that has not yet been assigned to a category or a transfer. 	You can only save the split transaction if the transaction amount has been exactly assigned.</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_splitPartCategory_info">Select a category for the split part.</string>
  <string name="help_ExpenseEdit_splitPartTransfer_info">Assign a transfer account to the split part.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_split_part_category_help_text">Opens the form for assigning a part of the split to a category.</string>
  <string name="menu_create_split_part_transfer_help_text">Opens the form for defining a part of the split as a transfer to another account.</string>
  <string name="menu_save_help_text">Save the data and close the form.</string>
  <string name="menu_save_and_new_help_text">Save the data, leave the form open for creating a new transaction with the same data.</string>
  <string name="menu_invert_transfer_help_text">Invert the direction of the transfer by swapping \'From\' and \'To\' account.</string>
  <!-- AccountEdit -->
  <string name="help_AccountEdit_title">Form for accounts</string>
  <string name="help_AccountEdit_info">The account is identified by its label, the description has only an informative purpose. The currency can be chosen easily from a list. You can define the type of an account as one of Cash, Bank, Asset, Liabilities, Credit Card. The type determines the available payment methods that you can configure under Settings -> Manage -> Payment Methods.</string>
  <!-- MethodEdit -->
  <string name="help_MethodEdit_title">Form for payment methods</string>
  <string name="help_MethodEdit_info">On this screen, you associate a payment method with account types. You can also define a label (with the exception of the predefined methods which have a fixed label that cannot be edited). Through a method\'s type, you determine if it is applicable for expenses (debit), income (credit) or both (neutral). You can also set a flag if transactions using this method are numbered (e.g. check numbers).</string>
</resources>
